<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>England's merry jester: or, Court, city and country jests new, and suitable to the humours of the times; witty and familiar, for the encrease of merriment, and improvement of friendly conversation, as they are used among the wits of the age. To which are added, as a second part, Bulls; banters, quibbles, repartees, pleasant stories, and poems: the qualifications of an expert town-wheedle; with the art and mystery of wheedling. All profitable, pleasant, and delightful. The like never before published. Done by a lover of merriment.</title>
            <author>J. S.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 189 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 100 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A61403</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S54</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219786</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831233</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831233</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35696</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A61403)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35696)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2040:29)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>England's merry jester: or, Court, city and country jests new, and suitable to the humours of the times; witty and familiar, for the encrease of merriment, and improvement of friendly conversation, as they are used among the wits of the age. To which are added, as a second part, Bulls; banters, quibbles, repartees, pleasant stories, and poems: the qualifications of an expert town-wheedle; with the art and mystery of wheedling. All profitable, pleasant, and delightful. The like never before published. Done by a lover of merriment.</title>
                  <author>J. S.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12], 180 p., [1] leaf of plates : ill.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by J. Wilde, for N. Boddington, at the Golden Ball, in Duck-Lane,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Engraved frontispiece.</note>
                  <note>The preface is signed: J. S.</note>
                  <note>"The second part: containing bulls, blunders, banters, quibbles, repartees, wheedles, and pleasant stories .." has caption title on p. 145; "The new art of wheedling" has caption title on p. 174; register and pagination are continuous.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>English with and humor --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>England's Merry Ieſter: OR, Court, City and Country JESTS, New, and Suitable to the Humours of the Times; Witty and Familiar, for the Encreaſe of Merriment, and Improvement of Friendly Converſation, As they are uſed among the Wits of the Age.</p>
            <p>To which are added, as a <hi>Second Part,</hi> Bulls, Banters, Quibbles, Repartees, Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant Stories, and Poems: THE <hi>Qualifications</hi> of an Expert <hi>Town-Wheedle;</hi> with the <hi>Art and Myſtery</hi> of <hi>Wheedling.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All Profitable, Pleaſant, and Delightful.</p>
            <p>The like never before Publiſhed.</p>
            <p>Done by a Lover of Merriment.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>J. Wilde,</hi> for <hi>N. Boddington,</hi> at the <hi>Golden Ball,</hi> in <hi>Duck-Lane,</hi> 1693.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="frontispiece">
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:3"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>bawdy scene</figDesc>
                  <head>
                     <l>Reader wee think the Pictuere is a Iest.</l>
                     <l>If not proceed and Mirth attends the rest.</l>
                     <l>If you can ſmile at this there is no doubt.</l>
                     <l>Ere halfe the Book is read you will Laugh.</l>
                  </head>
               </figure>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
         <div type="encomium">
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:4"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:4"/>
            <head>To the AUTHOR, Upon his <hi>New JESTS,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>IF Mirth and Merriment can give Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plauſe,</l>
               <l>In this you carry from the reſt the Cauſe:</l>
               <l>O'er Melancholy you a Triumph gain,</l>
               <l>And do with little Coſt, remove the Pain:</l>
               <l>Mirth here ſprings up, as from its native ſource;</l>
               <l>Here needs no Doctors Fees, nor Phyſick's Courſe,</l>
               <l>To cure the Patient: It's but to peruſe</l>
               <l>What you have writ, and that that pleaſes, chuſe:</l>
               <l>And you will find, whate'er is your Complexion,</l>
               <l>Some Balm, or Cordial-Powder, or Confection,</l>
               <l>That will reſtore Mirth to a drooping Mind,</l>
               <l>And render Thoughts diſturb'd with Grief, refin'd.</l>
               <l>This is not all: It will Diſcourſe improve;</l>
               <l>And in the mid'ſt of Dullneſs, Laughter move;</l>
               <l>Furniſh the private Wits with Merriment,</l>
               <l>And give the publick profeſs'd Ones content.</l>
               <l>It's true, and I muſt own it, That in Jeſt</l>
               <l>Many appear, but this I count the beſt:</l>
               <pb facs="tcp:35696:5"/>
               <l>In this Men ſuch Variety will find,</l>
               <l>As cannot miſs to pleaſe a changing Mind:</l>
               <l>Blow hot or cold, your humour here is ſuited;</l>
               <l>The Wiſe approv'd, the fooliſh are confuted:</l>
               <l>Converſe, by this, is ſcrutiniz'd, to ſee</l>
               <l>How moſt Mens Tempers with their Words agree:</l>
               <l>For he who from Friends takes a Jeſt unkind,</l>
               <l>When moſt they want him, will lag laſt be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hind.</l>
               <l>Then be good-natur'd, and for Merriment,</l>
               <l>One Hour a Day in reading, think well ſpent;</l>
               <l>And by conſid'ring well what here is writ,</l>
               <l>Your ſelf may, one day, ſet up for a Wit:</l>
               <l>For why, we ſee, the Wits of this Age boaſt</l>
               <l>Their Parts, in Jeſts and Rhimes, and Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, moſt;</l>
               <l>And he that can excell in this, is fam'd,</l>
               <l>Tho' ſome will ſay, He's but a Wil nick-nam'd.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:5"/>
            <head>THE Preface TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>SInce Mirth is very much conducing to the Health of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind, and conſequently to the Prolongation of
<pb facs="tcp:35696:6"/>Life, as well as for plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant Entertainment and Satisfaction to Humane Society; it is but reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable, all Inoffenſive Ways ſhould be ſtudied, to procure and continue it: Wherefore, among many others, I have thought it convenient to take this Method, ſeeing this way it may be had without Toil, and with little Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence of Mony or Time. If Jeſting was not ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved, as a ſpeedy An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tidote
<pb facs="tcp:35696:6"/>againſt Cares and Anxieties of Mind, I would fain know why ſo many wiſe Princes in divers Ages, have been at the Charge of Main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining fit, qualify'd Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons for this very purpoſe, who, with their well<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tim'd and ſeaſonable Jeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, have refreſhed their Minds, and render'd them calm and ſerene, which were before rumpl'd and toſs'd with perplexing Affairs of State, or other Anxieties.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:7"/>
            <p>But to come nearer to my purpoſe; I muſt let the Reader know, That great care has been taken, to put down nothing that may reaſonably give Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence to any underſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Perſon, or grate the modeſt Ear; but that they are drawn up ſmooth and pleaſant, the greater part being New, and ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver before Publiſhed, and all of them ſuch as moſt uſually are delivered in Company, to garniſh out
<pb facs="tcp:35696:7"/>Diſcourſe, and keep up Good-Humour. He muſt needs be of a very Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lancholy Temper, that ſome or other of theſe will not move to Laugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter.</p>
            <p>But by the way, let me tell you, If you would be taken for a good Jeſter, you muſt always obſerve to Time them well; that coming <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>at upon the Diſcourſe, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>r hitting the Thing you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>eavel at, they may have
<pb facs="tcp:35696:8"/>more Force, and better Acceptance with the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors. Avoid Profane Jeſting, by any means; for that cannot be plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, but to Profane Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons.</p>
            <p>And the better to fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh out this Book, that there may be nothing wanting, I have thought fit to add, as a <hi>Second Part,</hi> ſeveral <hi>Bulls, Drol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leries, Repartees, Banters</hi> and <hi>Pleaſant Stories</hi> With the <hi>Art of Whee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling,</hi>
               <pb facs="tcp:35696:8"/>now very much in Uſe.</p>
            <p>And ſo recommend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Book to your fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vourable Cenſures, I re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>READER,</salute> 
               <signed>Your humble Servant to Command, <hi>J. S.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div n="1" type="part">
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:9"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35696:9"/>
            <head>
               <hi>England</hi>'s Merry Jeſter; OR, Court, City and Country JESTS, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <div n="1" type="jest">
               <head>1.</head>
               <p>A Gameſter having borrowed Ten Pounds, and loſt it, ſent for Ten more, by the ſame Token that he had borrowed the like Summ before; Nay, reply'd his Friend, unwilling to venture further; you come only by Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d of Mouth, and may deceive me: therefore tell him, unleſs I ſee the Token, I ſhall not ſend him a Farthing.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="jest">
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:35696:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>2.</head>
               <p>A drunken Blade reeling out of a Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern, and on his way home-ward, found his Head ſo light, that his Heels ſcorn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to carry it any farther, fairly trip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped themſelves up, and laid him in the Kennel, where he took a pleaſant Nap; till the Watch-men coming their Rounds, found him a ſnoaring; and 'waking him, told him, he muſt Come before the Conſtable: Gad, tell the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, you Puppies you, ſaid he, that he had nothing to do with me, for I belong to the Scavenger.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="jest">
               <head>3.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman in a dark night had got a bit of Link of a Tavern-Drawer to light him home, it being ſo late, that the Link-Boys had left the Streets: but the Flame in a ſhort time coming ſo near, that it almoſt made his Fingers ſuffer Martyrdom, he drew out his Sword, and ſtuck it on the Point of it; when coming by a Watch-Houſe in that ſtrange poſture, the Conſtable called him before him, and demanded, why he walked the Streets in Terror at ſuch a ſeaſon, to Alarm and fright People with Fire and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35696:10"/>Sword; and began to read him a Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture of the great Miſchiefs that had been done by thoſe two miſchievous In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruments: To which our Spark reply'd, as he ſtaggered and tottered too and fro, Why, why, Mr. Conſtable, you are a very ſtrange Man, to talk at this rate; what, won't you allow me a Save-all to my Link? This Conceit ſo pleaſed the Conſtable, that he ſent a Watch-man to ſee him ſafe home.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="jest">
               <head>4.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Thomas Moor</hi> in King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth's time, was a Man of infinite Jeſts, who falling into that King's Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſure, and being to be Beheaded on <hi>Tower-Hill,</hi> ſaid to one that gave him his Hand, I prithee, Good fellow lend me thy Hand to get upon the Scaffold, but as for my coming down I take no heed; and when the Executioner was about to ſtrike the fatal Blow, Hold, Friend, ſaid he, let me put my Beard on one ſide, for although you have Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion to cut off my Head, you have nothing to do to cut my Beard: for whatever has been pretended, that has
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35696:11"/>committed no High-Treaſon, as being grown ſince I came into my Confine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="jest">
               <head>5.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Joceline Piercy,</hi> Brother to the Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> in Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi>'s days, being an Airy Spark, and very Ingenious; obſerving a Country-wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man had attended in the <hi>Lobby</hi> of the Council-Chamber ſeveral days, he de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded her buſineſs; who told him, ſhe had a Petition to deliver, in hopes of the Redreſs of a certain Grievance, and could get no body to deliver it for her. Let me ſee it then, ſaid he, and look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing upon it, Puh, this will never do your buſineſs, but I will draw up one inſtantly that ſhall prove Effectual: her Controverſie it ſeems was with the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of <hi>Moortclack,</hi> about ſtopping a Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter-courſe, that thereupon overflowed her ground, and did her much Damage. He wrote her one, and getting it pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented by a Friend, immediately re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tir'd. The Woman was called in, and the Clerk of the Council order'd to read it; who could not for a
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35696:11"/>time do it for laughing, till he was check<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and commanded to read it, which was in theſe words,
<q>
                     <l>The Parſon of <hi>Moortclack</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>With two Stone and a Stake,</l>
                     <l>Stops up my Water Lake,</l>
                     <l>Help, Lords, for Gods ſake.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p>Upon this, they allburſt out into Laugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and for the Fancy's ſake, made an Order, that the Parſon ſhould remove his two Stones and a Stake, and leave the good Woman's Water-courſe open.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="jest">
               <head>6.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Scoggin</hi> in his time, having affront<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Maids of Honour, and other Court Ladies, by throwing out ſatyri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Jeſts; they upon their Complaint, obtained he ſhould run the Gauntlet, and every one with a Switch have a blow at his naked Back; but before he began his Race, ſaid, <hi>I</hi> wonder that you ſhould be all thus bent againſt me, I know ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of you to be honourable and virtu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, but by this Tryal it will be known whom I meant; for ſhe that is guilty of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35696:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>the Charge I urged, will be ſure to ſtrike firſt: hereupon they ſtood gazing up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on each other, admiring who ſhould be ſhe; each forbearing to begin, till he run quite through them, and eſcap'd the Puniſhment deſign'd.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="jest">
               <head>7.</head>
               <p>One time he wanting Money, and meeting a Lord as he was walking mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing in the Court, ſet a good face on't to wheedle him out of a broad Piece, and coming up to him, ſaid, My Lord, I had a ſtrange dream laſt night, and now half of it is out, for I dreamed I met you here, which now proves ſo, and that you gave me a broad Piece: Well, ſaid the Lord, then I will make out the other part, and ſo gave it him; and then ſaid, Alack! I miſtook, give it me again, for that is a Piece my Miſtreſs gave me to keep for her ſake, which he readily did, in hopes of a better Gratui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty. Then ſaid the Lord, I'll now tell you my Dream, that it may be out like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, <hi>viz.</hi> I dream'd I gave a Fool Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, and he had not the Wit to keep it: and ſo he paſſed on, leaving <hi>Scoggin</hi>
                  <pb n="7" facs="tcp:35696:12"/>to ſcratch his Ears and vex at being out-witted.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="jest">
               <head>8.</head>
               <p>King <hi>James</hi> the Firſt abhorring Flat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terers, and being one day in the Park, where ſome Noble Men leap'd before him for a great Wager, he ſaid, Is this all you can do? is it the fartheſt you can leap? A Paraſite who ſtood at his El<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bow, ſaid it was nothing to what his Majeſty had done in his younger days; thinking thereby further to ingratiate himſelf: to which the King reply'd, By my Saul Man, thou lieſt; for I could never leap ſo far, by five foot.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="jest">
               <head>9.</head>
               <p>The ſame Monarch upon his Acceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion to the Engliſh Diadem, had ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral great Preſents made him; and a poor Gard'ner hearing that he gave large<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to the Preſenters, reſolved to try his Fortune; whereupon he preſented him with a Turnep of a vaſt bigneſs, and he conſidering the Man's poverty, ordered him a Hundred Pounds. A perſon who
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35696:13"/>had a very find Horſe, for which he was offer'd 120 broad Pieces: being inform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed of this, thought to himſelf, that if the King gave ſo much for the Preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of ſo ſmall a Value, he ſhould not miſs of trebble the Summ: and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly made a Preſent of his Horſe, which the King liked exceeding well; but having private Intimation of the Parties Expectations, he fruſtrated them, by only ordering the Hundred pound Turnep ſhould be given him to make his beſt on't: which Fruſtration caus'd him to go away, ſcratching his Ears,</p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="jest">
               <head>10.</head>
               <p>A Perſon having been notorious for Quarrelling, wounding divers, and at laſt killing a Man, Interceſſion was made for his Pardon, which this King granted: but ſuch Clemency not being ſufficient warning, he killed another; and when the like Suit was made, the King reply'd, Nay by my Saul Man, it was not he, but I that killed this Man; for if he had been hanged before, this party had been alive; therefore he ſhall dye for making me unwittingly guilty
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:35696:13"/>of Murther, and accordingly he was Executed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="jest">
               <head>11.</head>
               <p>The King being upon a Country Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſs, and at an Inn, after Dinner went privately from his Attendance, whil'ſt they were in the height of their Jolli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, and coming to the Stable, found the Hoſtler ſweating in currying down the Horſes; to whom he ſaid, Good Fellow, what News do you hear in theſe parts? what Diſcourſe have they of the King? Why truly Sir, reply'd he, nothing to the purpoſe, but that he makes a great many poor Knights. Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on this, the King retir'd, and ordered him to be ſent for; the Fellow being conſcious of what he had ſaid, trem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled at the conſequence, but go he muſt, and coming into the Preſence, he was ordered to kneel, which with ſome unwil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingneſs he did: Then the King draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out his Sword, which he ſuppoſed was for no other Intent, then to cut off his Head, cryed out for Mercy, and begged his Pardon; but was a little com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forted, when the Royal voice bid him
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:35696:14"/>Riſe up Sir <hi>Roger Clodpate</hi> Knight; telling him his Report was now verify'd, for he had made one poor Knight; and ſo diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſed him to occupy his former Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment of rubbing down the Horſes Heels.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="jest">
               <head>12.</head>
               <p>This King ſeperated from his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany in hunting a Stag, went to a mean Cottage, on the edge of a Forreſt; where he found an old Woman ſeething Pottage, and being keen in Appetite, deſired ſome of them, which ſhe pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented him; but being none of the cleanlieſt, and having unuſual Herbs in them, cauſed in him an extraordinary Belly ach, of which he complaining, ſhe immediately fetched a Bullet, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiring him to ſwallow it as a preſent Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy; when ſtraining to get it down, ſhe cry'd, O Sir, you have a very nar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row Throat, I have ſwallow'd it a hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred times upon the like occaſion, and never found any difficulty in it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="jest">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:35696:14"/>
               <head>13.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Archee</hi> the King's Jeſter, when Arch-Biſhop <hi>Laud</hi> bore a great Sway in King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt's time, being asked his Opinion of a Set of Coach-horſes that were preſented to the King; ſaid, they ſhould be Eccleſiaſticks, come from the pampering of good Benefices, by their Fatneſs, but were too unweildy for Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; making in his Compariſons Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flection on the Arch-Biſhop: which he highly reſenting, cauſed ſearch to be made for him, to cauſe him to be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed; but he could not be found, till ſome of his Friends prevailed with the King to make his Peace: And where then, ſaid he, do you think all this while I have hid my ſelf? We know not, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd they; Why, ſaid <hi>Archee,</hi> I'll tell you; even in the Chappel-Pulpit, for I knew his Grace never wou'd come there to look for me.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="14" type="jest">
               <head>14.</head>
               <p>A down-right Country Farmer com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to bring this great Prelate Rent for
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:35696:15"/>ſome Tenures he held of him, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving never before been in the preſence of any but a Juſtice or the Mayor of a Corporation, accoſted him, with May it pleaſe your Worſhip, at the ſame time giving a ſcrape with his Hob-nail Shoes, but was jogged by the Servants behind him, and order'd to ſay Grace inſtead of Worſhip; What, ſaid he, muſt I ſay Grace where there's no Meat? but if it be the faſhion here, 'tis an odd one; then lifting up his Hands, he ſaid, <hi>The Eyes of all things, &amp;c.</hi> and ſo went on, to the Admiration of the Biſhop, who took him to be diſtracted, till he found he had done it by Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>underſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="15" type="jest">
               <head>15.</head>
               <p>King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, riding a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſs, and coming to a Country Knight's Houſe, who though proud of the King's Viſit, yet his Coffers could not reach to a very ſumptuous Entertainment for ſo great a Train; but having very fine Orchards and Gardens, it being Fruit time of year, what wanted in Fiſh, Fowl, Sweet-meats, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> was ſupplyed by the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:35696:15"/>Tables being loaded with Pears, Apples, Plumbs, Nuts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> inſomuch, that the King ſaid, What means this? we ſhall ruin the Country: which a blunt Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try Fellow who waited hearing, and thinking to put a fine Gloſs upon the matter, replyed, Your Majeſty need not fear that, for we have ſo many, that we are forced to give them to the Hogs: which pretty Complement ſet the whole Company in a Laughter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="16" type="jest">
               <head>16.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Hugh Peters,</hi> the Bell-weather Holder-forth, who was a kind of a Buffoon Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter to <hi>Oliver Cromwell,</hi> Preaching at <hi>White-Hall</hi> before him, began com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend the Officers for their Courage and Bravery, telling how they had been Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vanced, what Favours they had receiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed from the Protector; but here's par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly one amongſt you that has been as deſerving as the beſt of you; a Man that has had Experience of Hemp in his Calling; for ſome ſay he's a Shoe-maker, others, that he's but a Cobler; but let him be which of theſe he will, his Name is <hi>Hewſon,</hi> and here ſits a ſleep under
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:35696:16"/>the Pulpit. This Banter upon the cob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling Colonel made ſuch a tittering a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong thoſe that ſate next to him, that he awak'd, and thinking all was done, was about to go out; which <hi>Peters</hi> per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiving, ſaid, Nay, Colonel, ſince you have had ſuch a large Nap, you are by this time ſober enough to take 'tother Glaſs; and turning up his Pulpit-glaſs, went on with another Hour's Harrangue, much to the like edifying purpoſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="17" type="jest">
               <head>17.</head>
               <p>The French Ambaſſadour reſiding at Court, in the Reign of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, to boaſt the Greatneſs and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of his Maſter, went vauntingly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout, ſhewing a Diſtich he had made;
<q>
                     <l>Una dies Lotheros Burgundos Hebdomas una,</l>
                     <l>Una domat Battavos Luna quid Annus agit.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p>This proud Inſult diſpleaſing the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Lord <hi>Rochester,</hi> ſince dead, he was reſolved to put upon the Monſieur, and looking over his ſhoulder, turn'd them thus into Engliſh.</p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:35696:16"/>
               <q>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Lorrain</hi> he ſtole; by Fraud he got <hi>Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gundy,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Holland</hi> he bought; but Faith, he'll pay for't one day.</l>
               </q>
               <p>Upon this, the French-man made his Complaint to the King, but to no purpoſe; the King telling him, he was a perſon that would have his Humours of that kind, do what he could.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="18" type="jest">
               <head>18.</head>
               <p>This Noble-Man being very early in St. <hi>James</hi>'s <hi>Park,</hi> walking and muſing for new Crotchets of Poeſie, met the King, with his Brother, and the Duke of <hi>Lauderdale,</hi> walking from <hi>White-Hall</hi> to St. <hi>James</hi>'s; the King ſeeing him, ſaid, How now, <hi>Rocheſter?</hi> what makes you ſo early here? I warrant you have ſome new-minted Fancies in your Head? Come, let us hear one of them; the Earl excuſed it, as not convenient; but the King preſſing it, promiſing he would not be angry whatever it was, he thus deſcanted on them:
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:35696:17"/>
                  <q>
                     <l>For Maiden-Head-Bargains, your Majeſty's beſt,</l>
                     <l>The Duke for his Valour and breaking a Jeſt;</l>
                     <l>And <hi>Lauderdale,</hi> that is ſo wondrous pretty,</l>
                     <l>By his Politicks, gains the Applauſe of the City.</l>
                  </q> O my Conſcience, ſays the King, he has Satyr'd upon us all: well, go thy ways, thou art an Arch Wag, and ſo they parted.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="19" type="jest">
               <head>19.</head>
               <p>King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second was a very merciful Prince to Offenders, and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended his Clemency to a great many that were condemn'd; the condemn'd Roll one day being preſented to him by the Recorder of <hi>London,</hi> to know his Pleaſure, who ſhould Suffer; ſeveral Courtiers being preſent, interceded ſome for one, and ſome for another; whom he croſſed out, till there was but one left; then he asked who ſpoke for him, but none anſwering, O my Conſcience, ſays
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:35696:17"/>the King, this is a poor Fellow, and wants Mony, I'll ſtand his Friend; and ſtruck him out.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="20" type="jest">
               <head>20.</head>
               <p>When the great Heat of Petitioning was one Foot, a Petition among others was Delivered by—which being read, King <hi>Charles</hi> looking upon thoſe that brought it, ſaid, very familiarly to them, Well, Neighbours, I cannot but wonder you ſhould trouble your ſelves about my Buſineſs, however, we'll defer it for this time; and tell the reſt of my Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, when I come to <hi>Windſor,</hi> I'll diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe it further with them over a Pot of Ale, and ſo diſmiſſed them; ſmiling at the Anſwer they were to return to the reſt of the Subſcribers.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="21" type="jest">
               <head>21.</head>
               <p>A Woman who was adapted to ſome-what of the Frailty of her Sex, being brought to bed of a Boy, her Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band ſitting by the Bed-ſide, was conſult<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing who ſhould be Goſſips, and amongſt others, he named a perſon who was by
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:35696:18"/>ſome ſuſpected to have a hand in the pye; ſaying, he knew he would ſtand: whereat lifting up her Hands, ſhe reply'd, O the Father! that you ſhould think of him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="22" type="jest">
               <head>22.</head>
               <p>A plump Country Laſs being in a <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> Service, her Maſter wheedled her to his Embraces, ſo that after repeated Dalliances, ſhe proved with Kid, and one day there being a Pig for Dinner, ſhe happening to Long for the Ears, eat them; as knowing, if they came to the Table, they would not fall to her ſhare, and therefore made ſure work be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore-hand; the Miſtreſs however miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing them, made Enquiry, and being told the naked Truth by the ſimple Girl, demanded how ſhe came to be in that con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition? Why truly and indeed forſooth, reply'd ſhe, by my Maſter's help; the Woman then wiſhfully looking upon her Husband, who ſate by, ſaid, Is this true? Yes indeed, reply'd he, I believe it may, And when was it done, ſaid ſhe? Why truly Sweet-heart, when you were ſick laſt: Ah! reply'd ſhe, with a Sigh, and
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:35696:18"/>was I ſo ſick, can a Woman be ſo ſick, that her Husband muſt needs go aſtray? O unkind Man—</p>
            </div>
            <div n="23" type="jest">
               <head>23.</head>
               <p>A Woman in the Country being in Labour, divers were called, and amongſt the reſt, an old Woman; but it being a cold Night, ſhe neglected to riſe till day-light, and then haſted to the houſe, and had notice the Woman was ſafely de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered; when ſtumbling at an old Cradle, where a ſick Pig was wrapped up in a piſs-burn'd Blanket; ſhe, for want of her Spectacles, miſtaking it for a Child, fell to kiſſing and ſlabbering it; crying, O pretty Babe, it is as like its own Father as if it had been ſpit out of his Mouth.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="24" type="jest">
               <head>24.</head>
               <p>A Country Laſs having been at <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> in a Service, and had gotten tolle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable good Rigging upon her; coming down again, had a great many brave Kinsfolks came to viſit her, amongſt the reſt a Widow-woman's Son fell in Love with her; but ſtumbling home from his Courtſhip, her Mother asked
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:35696:19"/>him whether at the parting he had kiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Mrs. <hi>Mary</hi> or not? No, indeed for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſooth, ſaid he, I forgot it; then reply'd ſhe, I charge you, Boy, upon my Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, go back and do it; leſt you be thought unmannerly, and diſgrace our Family: Away thereupon trudged Hob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nail; but the Door being lock'd, ſhe refuſed to let him in, it being very late, but proffer'd him the Favour he deſir'd through the Caſement; and finding him a ſimple Fellow, inſtead of her Face, preſented him her Breech, which he very amorouſly ſmuggled, and giving a ſcrape, went away very thankfully; and told his Mother at his Return, that now he liked Mrs. <hi>Mary</hi> better and bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter; becauſe he was ſure ſhe was a good Houſewife: How know you that, ſaid the old Woman? well enough, reply'd he, For ſhe had been late up a ſpinning, and had Toe in her Mouth when he buſs'd her.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="25" type="jest">
               <head>25.</head>
               <p>A witty young Man in the Country, having a Love for a Rich Farmer's Daughter, and ſhe the like for him;
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:35696:19"/>but he being poor, the Farmer would by no means conſent to the Marriage, which put the Spark upon a Stratagem, <hi>viz.</hi> going abroad with his Miſtreſs one Evening in the Fields, he pulled out his Knife, and cut a round hole in the ground, deſiring her to make Water in it, which ſhe modeſtly refuſed, till he entreated it again; urging, they ſhould both reap the Fruits of their Deſires by it; ſhe had no ſooner done this, but he fell to be-labouring the place with his ſtick, and ſo concealing the conceit, went home with her, and then with a kind Kiſs parted and went to an Ale-houſe, where his Companions began to pity his Diſappointment: No matter, ſaid he, let who will have her, I'm ſure I have pay'd her piſſing-hole ſufficient<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly This being taken in the worſt Senſe, ſoon came to the Ears of the Father and Mother, who, with open cries fell to reproaching their Daughter as a wicked naughty Wretch, to defile her ſelf, and ſlain her Family. The Maid remembring what had paſſed, took the Hint, and improved it; ſaying, if any ſuch thing had happened, it was their Faults, in hindring her from mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying
<pb facs="tcp:35696:20"/>
                  <pb n="22" facs="tcp:35696:21"/>with a Man ſhe ſo well loved O you young Whore then! ſaid the Old Man, do you confeſs it? Come Wife, continu'd he, let's ſend for the Rogue, and marry them, before it be noiſed any further; and accordingly by this Trick the Lovers obtained their Deſires with the conſent of all parties, which no Entreaties before could pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="26" type="jest">
               <head>26.</head>
               <p>A ſuper annuated Chamber-Maid perceiving the Midwife to be ſo well pay'd, and have a great deal of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys at her Miſtreſse's Chriſtenings, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to ſtudy that Art, and having got ſome Notions out of Books, decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red her ſelf a Proficient; giving warn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and reſolving to ſet up for a Mother Midnight: her Miſtreſs being a witty Woman, ſmiled at this, and to improve the Frollick, told her, ſhe highly ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved of her Undertaking, and doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed not her Skill; adding, ſhe ſhould try her firſt practice on a young Couſin of hers, who was to come from <hi>London</hi> to lye in at her houſe in a few days: for this
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:35696:21"/>promiſe ſhe returned her Miſtreſs many Thanks, and prepared her ſelf with Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſaries. In the mean while the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs and ſome Gentlewomen whom <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he had acquainted with the Intreague, procured a ſmock-fac'd beardleſs Youth, who, dreſſed in Womans cloaths, came <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s from <hi>London,</hi> and paſſed for the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected Couſin, with a Cuſhion under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>eath for a great Belly: Throws were pretended, and the new Midwife called, who immediately fell to grabbling, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>atching hold of his Label of Mortali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>y, fell a tugging at it, as ſuppoſing it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>art of the Child, crying, Now all hands <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o help, for I'll aſſure you 'tis Labour, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or here is one Leg in the World al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready; at which they all burſted out <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nto a Laughter, till their ſides ak'd, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd Mother Midnight finding her Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>take, left not only her Service for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ame, but forſwore the Practice for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>er, ſeeing ſhe had been ſo fooled at <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e firſt Bout.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="27" type="jest">
               <head>27.</head>
               <p>A Country Laſs coming up to Town <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>n a Pack-horſe to ſeek her Fortune,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:35696:22"/>had the good luck to be hired as a Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant to an an old Rich Mercer, who was a Batchelour, and pleaſed him ſo well, that at laſt he married her; he<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Brother, and the top of her own Kin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred, who was a down-right hone<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Plough-man, hearing of his Siſter's pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>motion, threw by his Paddle-ſtaff, pu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> on his Holy-day cloaths, took up h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Quarters Wages, and up to <hi>London</hi> h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> came; and knowing the Streets by th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Direction of a Letter, though not th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Houſe, enquir'd from Door to Door fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> his Siſter <hi>Joan,</hi> who had lately marrie<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> her Maſter, till at laſt he was ſo luck<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> to find the right, where he was highl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> welcomed, and being at Dinner, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> old Mercer ſaid, Well, Brother-in-Law as I now muſt call you, I am glad <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſee you, or any of my Wife's Relation<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> ſhe has been a good Servant to me, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> I hope ſhe'll make as good a Wiſe; w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> have a plentiful Eſtate, and all I wiſh <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> a Child to inherit it, which yet we hav<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> no hopes of: at this <hi>Dick</hi> looking wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> fully upon Madam his Siſter, blunt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> ſaid, How now <hi>Joan,</hi> what art the turned a barren Sow in <hi>London?</hi> the waſt not wont to be ſo in the County
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:35696:22"/>and though ſhe frown'd, beckon'd, and made dumb ſigns for him to hold his Peace, yet he went on: And well, Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>(continu'd he)</hi> as for an Heir, you need not trouble your ſelf, for ſhe has a thumping Boy in the Country, got by <hi>Will. Dobs,</hi> her Maſter's Thraſher; and the Pariſh would be glad to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charg'd of it. At this, the Old Man ſtar'd, and Madam went bluſhing from the Table, that a Fool's Bolt ſo unwit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tingly ſhot, had ruined her Reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="28" type="jest">
               <head>28.</head>
               <p>A Woman having a Croſ-grain'd Husband, hard to pleaſe; ſhe deſir'd him to write down what ſhe ſhould do, and what ſhe ſhould not do, that ſhe might not err in her Performance: this was done, and ſhe well obſerved her Rules; when one day going a mile or two to viſit a Friend, the good Man got light-headed, and on his Return home, reeled into a Ditch, calling to his Wife to help him out: Indeed Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band <hi>(ſaid ſhe)</hi> I remember no ſuch Article in my Orders, but I'll go home
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:35696:23"/>and ſee; and if there be, I'll come and help you, or elſe you muſt get out as well as you can, for I am reſolved not to break them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="29" type="jest">
               <head>29.</head>
               <p>An unmarried Gentlewoman deſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous to have her Picture drawn, ſent for a Limner, and gave him Directions to draw it at Large, in full Proportion, but to repreſent a Virgin: he having drawn the Face to her Content, drew the Drapery and other Parts at home; but, when ſhe ſaw it, ſhe was diſguſted, becauſe it was not of Stature and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to her Body: O Madam, <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> I leſſened it on purpoſe; for had it been ſo Large, none would have believ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed it could have repreſented the Picture of a Virgin in this early Age.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="30" type="jest">
               <head>30.</head>
               <p>A Girl about Ten Years old, had got a trick of confidently ſtaring in Mens Faces when they were talking; for which her Mother reproved her, ſaying; Daughter, our Sex enjoyns us
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:35696:23"/>Modeſty, and you ought to be baſhful, and look downward when you are in Mens Company, and not to ſtand gazing and gaping as if you were looking Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bies in their Eyes: to which the pert Girl reply'd, This Lecture forſooth, ſhould have been read in the former ignorant Ages, but every Age grows wiſer and wiſer; that Maids of this Age know better: Men indeed, may look down on the primitive Duſt, from whence they were taken, but Man be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing our Original, I will ſtare in their Faces, ſay what you can to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="31" type="jest">
               <head>31.</head>
               <p>A wealthy Citizen, and once a Man of great Authority, conſidering how Time improves Underſtanding, was heard to ſay, that every Age grew wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer and wiſer, than that which preceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ed it; for (<hi>continu'd he</hi>) thus I prove it; My Father was wiſer than my Grand-father, I am wiſer than my Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and my Daughter is wiſer than us all three.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="32" type="jest">
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:35696:24" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>32.</head>
               <p>A Widower, whoſe former Wife had lead an unquiet Life, by reaſon of his Inſufficiency, came a courting to a brisk Laſs, who thereupon refuſed; but her Mother chid her, ſaying, She was a Fool to refuſe ſuch an Offer, ſeeing he's very Rich, and would maintain her very bravely: Ay, but Mother, <hi>(reply'd ſhe,)</hi> If we ſhould chance to fall out, what ſhall we do for a Peace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maker to reconcile us? In troth, let who will take him, I had rather go in my Hair-Lace and Slippers with a Cock of the Game, than to ruſsle in Silks, to be trod by a Capon.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="33" type="jest">
               <head>33.</head>
               <p>A Country Squire of a home-ſpun breeding, Courted a brisk Girl, Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to a Rich Farmer, who by her Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's Conſent, was perſuaded to marry him, he having a pretty good E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate; and accordingly the day was ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed: but one day eſpying a Mare, on which the old Man uſed to ride to
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:35696:24" rendition="simple:additions"/>Market, and for her eaſie going was much eſteemed, which he deſired into the Bargain; but being refuſed, flung away in a Huff, and told him, he might then keep his Daughter: the Girl was mighty glad of this Rupture, but ſoon after repenting his Folly, he came a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, when none but ſhe was at home; but ſhe made as if ſhe knew him not, Why, this is ſtrange <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> that you ſhould ſo ſoon forget me; why, I am ſuch a one, O, I cry you mercy Sir! <hi>(reply'd ſhe)</hi> You are the Gentleman that came a wooing to my Father's Gray Mare; why truly, your Miſtreſs is gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zing in the Orchard; you may go and make your Addreſſes to her, if you pleaſe. This Repartee ſo daſhed him out of Countenance, that he never had the ſa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e to ſpeak to her afterward.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="34" type="jest">
               <head>34.</head>
               <p>A Woman having often up<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>aided her Husband for following Whores; he came one night, expecting a Juniper-lecture, having a Gut filled with Ox Blood, tyed at both ends, in his Breeches, he miſſed not his Expectation; for ſhe
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:35696:25"/>preſently began to open at him in the old Dialogue: Well Wife <hi>(ſays he)</hi> ſince this breeds our difference, I'll eaſe you of your Jealouſie, by removing the Cauſe of it; and ſo in a furious manner, pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling out his Knife, cut the Gut, and threw it in the fire: the Woman ſeeing the Blood, and thinking he had deſtroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed her Play-fellow, run ſcreaming out, crying for help, for that her Husband had murther'd himſelf, and a great ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Women coming in, found him on the Floor in a counterfeit Swoon: an old Woman among the reſt, undertook to ſearch the Wound, and ſadly aſſured them, it was too true, for his Guts were all in his Breeches: O then ſaid the Wife, I had rather he had cut his Head off.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="35" type="jest">
               <head>35.</head>
               <p>A Company of Roaring Blades com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into a Houſe, called for Wenches, but there happened to be but one at that time in waiting; at which they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to bluſter; ſaiyng, What a Pox, have you no more Whores, Landlord? No Sirs, <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> not at preſent, but by
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:35696:25" rendition="simple:additions"/>and by I ſhall; and in the mean time if you pleaſe, I'll ſend you up my own Wife.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="36" type="jest">
               <head>36.</head>
               <p>Two Country Fellows going by Saint <hi>Pauls,</hi> as it is now Magnificent in build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſays one to the other, (who ſtood with his Mouth at half Cock,) look you here <hi>Robin,</hi> here's a great Houſe, I<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ſe warrant it coſt Vorty Shillings buil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding: Ay, reply'd the other, Vorty and Vorty to that. Nay, hold you there <hi>Robin,</hi> not too many Vorties; for my Vather had a Barn built for Viſty Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="37" type="jest">
               <head>37.</head>
               <p>A Merry Wench perceiving a Fellow with a Torn pair of Breeches ſit ſtrad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and his Whim-wham hanging out, ſaid, Prithee <hi>Harry</hi> what's all this? Why, only my Purſe and Pack-thread: Say you ſo; <hi>(ſaid ſhe)</hi> why then my Purſe being cut, Prithee lend me your Pack-thread to mend it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="38" type="jest">
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:35696:26" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>38.</head>
               <p>Two Gentlemen travelling, and ſpy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing at a Brook in a Field, by the way<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide, a bouncing Country Laſs, with her Coats truſſed up to the middle of her Thighs, bucking her Cloaths; ſays one to the other, let us put upon this Wench. I'll venture a Bottle, ſays his Companion, ſhe anſwers you. Done, ſays the other: Then Sweet-heart <hi>(ſays he)</hi> what ails your Thighs to look ſo red? O Sir, <hi>(reply'd ſhe)</hi> I carry fire in mine Arſe, and want your Noſe for a Bucket to take up water to quench it: Upon this unexpected Repartee, he durſt not make a ſecond Attack, but yielded his Wager loſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="39" type="jest">
               <head>39.</head>
               <p>A Parſon over-ſeeing the mending of a Cauſey before his Deor, a Noble-man riding by, thought to joak upon him, ſaying, Well Doctor, I ſee you are men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding the way; but it ſeems it is not the way to Heaven: No, my Lord, <hi>(re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd he)</hi> if it were ſo, I ſhould look
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:35696:26"/>upon it as a great wonder to ſee your Lordſhip come this way.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="40" type="jest">
               <head>40.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow mounted between two Dorſers in <hi>Bartholomew</hi> Fair, ſate gaping at the jugling Tricks of the <hi>Jack Puddings,</hi> whilſt four arch Fellows ſhoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering up his Pack-ſaddle, ungirthed it, and drew his Horſe from under him, which they carryed into a neighbour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Inn: the Fellow all this while look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſtedfaſtly up to the Scaffold; whilſt being weary with ſupporting him, they ſlip'd aſide, and let him fall ſqualch to the ground: whilſt this amazed him, and made him ſtare about, one came with a ſnip of Hoſe-hair in his Hand, ſaying, he ſaw the Horſe ſink into the ground, and catching by his Tail, tho' he could not hold him, had plucked off that Hair: The Fellow took it for Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juration, and on his Knees beſought them to reſtore his Keffel; but no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing would do, till he had depoſited all the Mony he had taken at Market for his Butter and Eggs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="41" type="jest">
               <pb n="34" facs="tcp:35696:27"/>
               <head>41.</head>
               <p>One having ſtoln an Alarum Watch, ſtiffly denyed it before the Juſtice, ſo that upon the ſlender Evidence, he was diſcharged; but before he got out of the Hall, the Alarum went, and he was thereupon ordered to be brought back again; at which he cryed out, O what hard <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>uck have I! that I, could ſo eaſily baffle both Juſtice and Conſtable, and yet am trappan'd by the Watch.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="42" type="jest">
               <head>42.</head>
               <p>A Drover driving ſome Sheep through a narrow paſſage where the Trap-door of a Cellar was open, a black Ram fell in, and it being night, the reſt were driven on, without it being miſs'd: The Boy being ſent down for Drink, and ſeeing a black thing, with ſhining Eyes, came running up in a manner breath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs crying out, the Devil was in the Cell<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>; the Maſter going down to ſee, came up more affrighted; whereupon a Parſona little fuſter'd, being in the Houſe, undertook to Exorciſe the ſuppoſed De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon, as moſt proper to his Function; and ſo with his Book and his Candle went down. The Ram no ſooner heard
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:35696:27"/>him make a great noiſe, but he came running full drive at him; the Parſon ſtarting at this unexpected Aſſault, and throwing his Arms abroad, one of his Sleeves catched hold on a Tenter-hook, whereupon in the Fright, thinking he had been in Belzebub's Paws, throwing away his Book and Candle, cryed out with a lamentable Voice, Help! help! he has me, he has me: which ſo fright<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed thoſe above, that inſtead of coming to his Aſſiſtance, they all run out of Doors, and left him to ſhift for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="43" type="jest">
               <head>43.</head>
               <p>An ordinary Shentleman of <hi>Wales</hi> travelling to <hi>London</hi> to ſeek his Fortune, and being put to hard ſhifts, borrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Silver Tankard at an Inn where he lay, which being found upon him, he was Tryed at the <hi>Old-Baily,</hi> and there burnt in the Hand; which narrow eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cape of hanging, made him haſte back again to the Mountains: upon his re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn, one of his Country-men enquired of his Adventures; O <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other rare Things, hur met with
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:35696:28"/>the cunningeſt Fortune-tellers imagina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, who looking on her, told her, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther her ſhould live or die, and that hur might the better remember what they ſaid, it was writ with an Iron Pen in hur Hand.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="44" type="jest">
               <head>44.</head>
               <p>Another Welſh-man who had been whipp'd at the Carts-arſe, and his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion hang'd; upon his Return, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing demanded what was become of the latter, <hi>(reply'd hur)</hi> was pravely marry'd. Are you ſure on't, <hi>(ſaid they?)</hi> Yes, Plutter-a-nails was hur, for hur very well remember, hur danc'd ſuch a Shigg at her Wedding, as hur never danc'd in all hur life before.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="45" type="jest">
               <head>45.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Teague</hi> an Iriſh-man, being Servant to an Engliſh Gentleman, his Maſter go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Bowling-Green, and forget<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting a pair of Bowls he had cauſed to be made for his own playing, ſent <hi>Teague</hi> to fetch them; who miſtaking him, went unto the next Cloſe to fetch
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:35696:28"/>the Bull, but he would not come with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the Cows, ſo he brought them al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together, and drove them into the Green. Sirrah, (ſays his Maſter) what's the meaning of this? where are my Bowls? Why, Dear Joy <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> here is thy Bull; but upon my Shoul, I cou'd not get the damn'd Bitch to come with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out his Moder and Siſters, and dat be de Reoſhon I ſtay'd ſo long, hoping dou wilt not be angry. The ſimplici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Fellow, put them all preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly into a fit of Laughter, and induced his Maſter of forgive him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="46" type="jest">
               <head>46.</head>
               <p>Remember, (ſays a Gentleman to Iriſh <hi>Donnel</hi>) that you mind me to write a Letter, and ſend you to morrow mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning to ſuch a place; Yes, Dear Joy, <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> and ſo getting up the next morning, away he trudged Three Miles, without ſpeaking to his Maſter; being come to the Houſe, the Porter asked him his buſineſs, or what he come for. By my Shoul Joy, <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> I cannot tell; Why, who ſent you, (ſays the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,) Why, my Maſter bid me bring a
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:35696:29"/>Letter. Where is it? (ſays the other) I cannot tell. (ſaid the Iriſh-man) Who did write it? In good troth I cannot tell; <hi>(continu'd he)</hi> for I came away before <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e was up: The Man ſeeing him block<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>h, reſolved to put a Trick upon him, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> eupon ordered one of his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ervants <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> a Wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>p's Neſt, and catch about <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> in a Box: this done, he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> knew what his Maſter <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> him for, <hi>viz.</hi> was a Box of Silk-Worm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> but he muſt put them in his Breeches to keep them warm, or they would die; he did it accordingly, but had not gone far on his way, but the box opened, and out came Mon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſieur Yellow Jackets, fixing their Launces in his Thighs and Buttocks; which made him caper, run and roar like one poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed with a Fury.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="47" type="jest">
               <head>47.</head>
               <p>Another Gentleman having one of this Nation to his Footman, as wiſe as the reſt; order'd him to ſtep over the way to ſuch a Tavern, and ask if he were there: the Fellow very ignorant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly went, and returning, ſays his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter,
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:35696:29" rendition="simple:additions"/>Am I there or no? No, be my Shoul Joy, they ſay dee be not there, but thou wilt be there by and by.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="48" type="jest">
               <head>48.</head>
               <p>Two bouncing Laſſes waſhing them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves at a Spring in an Orchard, it happen'd whilſt they were merry and daſhing one another; a Fellow that came to ſteal ſome Fruit, lay ſnug in a Tree, whoſe Boughs hung over the Water, but peeping out of Curioſity too low, his hold ſlipp'd, and ſouze he ſell in, crying out, miſerably he ſhould be drowned: the naked Laſſes frighted hereat, left their Cloaths behind them, and ſled amain. The old Man their Father, was juſt ſhutting the Door as they came to it; but they ruſhing in, boat him down backwards, and running up ſtairs, covered themſelves in the Bed. The Old Man thus overthrown, lay ſprawling and crying out Thieves, and Murder; when the Neighbours com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in to demand the cauſe of his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation, O! <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> there are Thieves in my Houſe, deſperate Ruſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ans, all in Buff, with black Bandileers
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:35696:30" rendition="simple:additions"/>under their Waiſts, are run up ſtairs: This ſtartled them at firſt, but the truth being known, turned their Fear into Laughter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="49" type="jest">
               <head>49.</head>
               <p>A Prieſt viſiting a Party that was ſick, and without hope of Recovery, proceeded to comfort him, ſaying, If he dyed, he need not fear to be car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried to Heaven on Angels Wings: That will do well <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> with a faint Voice, for I am ſo weakned with my Sickneſs, I ſhall never get there on foot.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="50" type="jest">
               <head>50.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman ſending his Iriſh Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant into the Mew, to ſee whether his Hawks had Caſt, and he ſeeing one that had got his Hood off, playing with the other, and ſomtimes laying hold of his Head; he run in, and aſſured his Maſter, that one of them were about to Caſt: How do you know that? ſays his Maſter Why, by St. <hi>Patrick's</hi> Shoe-buckle, there
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:35696:30" rendition="simple:additions"/>be the great ſhign of it, for the other Hawk is holding his Forehead.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="51" type="jest">
               <head>51.</head>
               <p>A Country Yeoman marrying a Farmer's Buxom Daughter, but ſhe ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving a greater Kindneſs for another, had promis'd him her Maiden-head; and whil'ſt all were in the height of Merriment, they two retir'd into a back Milk-houſe, and there the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe was made good; but before the Sport was well ended, her Mother came in, and diſcovering what had paſſed, fell a ratling her extreamly, whil'ſt her Gallant ſneaked away. The Bridegroom hearing the noiſe, came and deſired to know what the matter was? O Son! ſays the old Woman, the Baggage has juſt now carck'd a Pipkin that has been kept without a Flaw theſe Nineteen Years: O Law! <hi>(ſays Clodpate)</hi> who cou'd not reach the meaning on't; is that all? Pray don't be angry, and here is a Groat to buy another.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="52" type="jest">
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:35696:31"/>
               <head>52.</head>
               <p>A Woman who had a drunken Husband, hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nking to reclaim him by Affright<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, put him once into a Coffin, and and laid him in a Vault, where being dead drunk, he ſlept all Night; the next morning ſhe knock'd ſo loud at the door of the Vault, that he awaking asked who was there? One <hi>(ſaid ſhe)</hi> that is come to bring Meat to the Dead <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> If you had brought Drink <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> you had been welcome, but for Meat I have no occaſion for, and therefore may carry it back again. O miſera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Woman that I am! (ſaid the Wiſe, what a hard Fortune is mine, to have a Husband that will be drunk even in his Grave.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="53" type="jest">
               <head>53.</head>
               <p>A Brisk Laſs having married a Tay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor, carryed him to ſee her Friends in the Country, where ſome Wenches gig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and being heard to ſay, <hi>Margery</hi> has marryed a Taylor, good lord! what <hi>(ſaid ſhe)</hi> replying ſharply, wou'd
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:35696:31"/>you have had me a marryed an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="54" type="jest">
               <head>54.</head>
               <p>An old Knight, who along time had a Female Help-mate, called a Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper; who had ſo well tickled his Fancy, that when he dyed, he left her his Coach and Horſes, and Five Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred a Year: in requital of which Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traordinary Benificence, ſhe Erected him a Monument, where among o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Things, his Figure lay along at Large, and hers was placed kneeling at its Feet with a Book, as if Reading: An Arch Wag ſeeing this, who was no ſtranger to their Intreagues, writ under it with a piece of Charcole, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <q>
                  <l>Though good Sir <hi>Harry</hi> wou'd not Marry,</l>
                  <l>He lov'd the Pleaſure out of meaſure:</l>
                  <l>When he liv'd, and had his Feeling,</l>
                  <l>She was Lying, he was Kneeling.</l>
                  <l>But now he's Dead, and paſt his Feeling,</l>
                  <l>He is Lying, ſhe is Kneeling.</l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div n="55" type="jest">
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:35696:32"/>
               <head>55.</head>
               <p>A Gentlewoman, who in her Life<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time was of but light Fame, and ſo Luſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, that ſhe labour'd to Sue out a Divorce againſt her Husband for Inſufficiency; but dyed before it could be obtained: whereupon laying a Stone over her, he cauſed theſe Lines to be Cut on it.</p>
               <q>
                  <l>She's dead, who living, no Man e're cou'd pleaſe,</l>
                  <l>No natural Engine her hot Luſt could eaſe,</l>
                  <l>But now behold the Wonders Death can do,</l>
                  <l>One Stone ſufficeth her, we plainly ſhew,</l>
                  <l>Who in her Life-time wan't content with Two.</l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div n="56" type="jest">
               <head>56.</head>
               <p>A Weaver's Wife in <hi>Spittle-Fields,</hi> up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Death of her Husband, ordered a Maſon to lay a Stone on his Grave<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> and being deſirous to have ſome Word<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> upon it, knew not what; at laſt it cam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> into her Head, <hi>viz. Here lyeth the Bod<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> of</hi> John Ball, <hi>Weaver of</hi> Spittle-Fields
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:35696:32"/>And what more? ſays the Maſon, who was a Thick-skull'd Fellow at Invention. That's all, ſays the Woman; upon this, he thinking ſhe meant the laſt Words for a Rhime, ſet it down in this man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner.</p>
               <q>
                  <l>Here lyeth the Body of <hi>John Ball,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Weaver of <hi>Spittle Fields,</hi>—That's all.</l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div n="57" type="jest">
               <head>57.</head>
               <p>In another place, a Man having been very troubleſome to his Neighbours, they were all glad when he died, yet in Remembrance of him, clubb'd for a Stone, upon which were Engraved theſe Lines.</p>
               <q>
                  <l>Here lies the Body of <hi>John Dry,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Ho! ho! do's he ſo? and there let him lie;</l>
                  <l>If you diſturb him he will have a Claw,</l>
                  <l>His very Ghoſt with you will go to Law.</l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div n="58" type="jest">
               <head>58.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow, who had never ſeen a Coach before, obſerving one come rattling along with a Gentlewoman in
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:35696:33"/>it; demanded of one that came riding behind, what that Trundling-Houſe was call'd? who reply'd, a Coach: Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry fine, reply'd the Countryman: And who is that Gay Woman in it? Why the Queen of Hearts, ſaid the other; In troth <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> I thought ſo, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe the Knave of Clubs was ſo cloſe at her heels; for they are always ſhuffled together.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="59" type="jest">
               <head>59.</head>
               <p>A Mountebank riding along the Road, ſaw a great Croud in another Road a little diſtant, and ſent his Man to ſee what the matter was; who come ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding back in great haſt and Conſterna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, crying out before he came at him, O Maſter! fly, fly, for your Life; What ails the the Fool? what's the matter? ſaid our Doctor? O Sir! ſaid his Man, there's a Fellow a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>going to be hanged for kil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling a Man, and you have killed forty to my knowledge in your time, with your Pills and Potions.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="60" type="jest">
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:35696:33"/>
               <head>60.</head>
               <p>A ſwinging ſtomach'd Fellow be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſet to a large piece of Roaſt-Beef, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut ſometimes at one end, and ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times at another; the Miſtreſs of the Houſe entreated him to cut fair, and not ſpoil the faſhion of the Meat: Don't <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ou take care no care for that; <hi>(reply'd <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e)</hi> it matters not where I out, for I <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o intend to make both ends and the middle meet, before I go: and he prov<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed as good as his word; for he eat it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ll up, to the Admiration of all the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="61" type="jest">
               <head>61.</head>
               <p>Counſellour <hi>Marriot</hi> the great Eater, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>argaining with a Man that know him <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ot, to fill his Belly with Gammon of Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>on for a Shilling, he preſently devoured <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ne Gammon; at which the Man be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>an to grumble, ſaying, He had put it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nto his Breeches, or convey'd it out at <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he Window, for he was conſident, no Man could ever eat it; it weighed <hi>(ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>)</hi> Nine Pound and half: Puh, thou art
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:35696:34"/>a ſilly Fellow, <hi>(ſays Marriot)</hi> and doſt not underſtand what belongs to eating: I'll wager you the price of both, I eat another. Done, ſaid the Cook, and fetch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed another; ſtanding by till he had eat above half, and was going on to the reſt; then he ſnatched it away, ſaying, Certainly thou art the Devil; for none but the Devil cou'd devour at ſuch a rate: and ſo without taking a penny of his Money, entreated him to be pack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="62" type="jest">
               <head>62.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth, deſigning to Wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> againſt <hi>France,</hi> ordered a Rough Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage of Defiance to be carried to the French King, which was ſo grating, that the Meſſenger doubted of his Life if he delivered it: ſaying, The French King would undoubtedly take his Head off reply'd old <hi>Harry</hi> ſternly, If he dares to do it, I will revenge the Affront, in taking off the Heads of a Thouſand o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> his Subjects: But alas! Sir, ſaid the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, what good will that do me, when I have loſt mine? for I do not believe any of theirs will fit my Shoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="63" type="jest">
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:35696:34"/>
               <head>63.</head>
               <p>A Lady having a Lap-Dog, that ſhe was very fond of; one day the maid hapen'd to beat him for a naughty Trick, and my Lady hearing his Cry, came running to his Reſcue; demanded what he had done? and began to chide her rough uſage of her beloved Whelp. Madam, <hi>(ſays the Wench)</hi> he deſerves this Correction, and worſe; if you knew all, you'd ſay ſo: Why, what has he done? tell me quickly, Nothing, Madam, but you having careleſsy left your Dreſſing-Box open, he has very unmannerly untruſſed a Point amongſt your Lady ſhip's paints and Perfumes.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="64" type="jest">
               <head>64.</head>
               <p>A Taylor's and a Baker's Boy meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing together, Come, ſays the firſt, let us go and crack a Pot, we ſhall ne'er want Money at our Trades, as long as there are Backs and Bellies, and our Maſters have chalk'd out a way to pinch and Steal for our Expences. I know not what Tricks your Maſter has ſhewed
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:35696:35"/>you, (ſays the Baker's Boy) but I'll take it upon me to ſay, that my Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter is as honeſt a Man, as ever liv'd by Bread.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="65" type="jest">
               <head>65.</head>
               <p>A Perſon ſeeing a Fray in the ſtreet, and being Pot-valiant, wou'd needs thruſt himſelf into it; got a ſhrew'd crack'd Crown, which obliged him to ſend for a Surgeon; who being long at Probing; he asked him what he was doing? Why ſearching (ſaid the other) For what? (ſaid the Patient) To ſee if your Brains were not hurt, (ſays the Surgeon.) Truly Sir, <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> you may ſpare that labour, for if I had had any Brains, I had eſcaped this Miſchief, by being wiſe enough to keep out of a Fray, wherein I had no Concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="66" type="jest">
               <head>66.</head>
               <p>A Man coming to a Painter to draw him a Bear upon a Sign-board, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to be brought to but a very indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent Price; (ſays the Painter) the
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:35696:35"/>Chain and Collar muſt be Leaf-Gold, and that is dear: Puh (ſays the Man) I care not a Pin whether there be any Chain or Collar. So drawn it was at his price, but with ſuch ſlight Colours, that the next great Rain waſhed it off. The Alehouſe-Man hereupon ſent for the Painter, and reproached him for a Cheat; O <hi>(ſays he)</hi> did I not tell you that by all means, you ſhould have had a Collar and a Chain; but being left looſe, has e'en run away, and all that I can ſay to the matter is, you muſt find him where you can.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="67" type="jest">
               <head>67.</head>
               <p>A Scotch-man intending to ſet up a Two penny-Chop-Ordinary, went to a Carvers, and bargain'd with him to Carve him a Bare Head for his Sign, and he taking him for a Barber or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riwig-maker, Carved him one accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly: but ſeeing it, diſliked it; (ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing) Upon my Saul Man, in geud faith this is not the Bare Head I meant; No (ſays the Carver) what then? Why, a Bare Head of the Sows Husband who has little Grices and Gruntlins follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:35696:36" rendition="simple:additions"/>her, crying a-week, a-week. O now I underſtand you, (ſays the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver) you mean a Boars Head, Yes, by Saint <hi>Andrew</hi> do I; (ſaid <hi>Jockey</hi>) and ſo they agreed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="68" type="jest">
               <head>68.</head>
               <p>In Popiſh Times, when the Holy Rood was ſet up; a Country Carver had made ſuch an ugly Image, that it ſtood like a Bug-bear to fright the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren from Church, ſo that the people would not contribute to pay him; he thereupon warned them before the Mayor of the Town; who told them, 'twas reaſon the Man ſhould be pay'd for his Labour, and if they lik'd it not for a God, they might make a Devil of it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="69" type="jest">
               <head>69.</head>
               <p>A Fellow being ſharply reproved by his Neighbour's Wife, for conſerting with Lewd Women: Why, what would you have me to do <hi>(ſays he)</hi> I am a Batchelour and reſolve not to marry; yet if I could have an opportunity to
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:35696:36"/>kiſs an honeſt Woman when I had an occaſion, it would wean me: Hark you then <hi>(ſaid ſhe)</hi> whiſpering in his Ear, my Husband won't come home to night, and I'll leave the back Door open for you, you know the way to my Bed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="70" type="jest">
               <head>70.</head>
               <p>A Woman having a drunken Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band, who when ſhe ſcolded at him, u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to beat her when he came home in that pickle; whereupon ſhe went to a Doctor to know what would cure him of that boiſterouſneſs; who by her Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe, perceiving that her Tongue oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion'd her hard Uſuage, told her, he would give her a Water, which if ſhe held in her Mouth when ſhe let him in, and till he was in bed, he ſhould have no power to beat her. The ſilly Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man put it in practice, and whil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> her Mouth was ſo ſill'd, ſhe could not uſe her Clacker, and ſo eſcap'd many a bang'd ſides: Mr. Doctor got a Crown a week of her, till one of her Goſſips diving into the Myſtery; told her, ſhe might as well ſave the Charge, and hold her
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:35696:37"/>Tongue without it and conſequently be ſecure from beating.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="71" type="jest">
               <head>71.</head>
               <p>A Country-man being ſent by a Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman to his Son with ſome Moneys, who was a Student in the <hi>Temple,</hi> and finding a Note in the Key-hole, <hi>viz. I am gone to the Devil,</hi> he ſtarted, and his Hair ſtood an end, and for a while knew not what to think or ſay; till ſuppoſing himſelf near the Conſines of Hell, and that he might be fetched to accompany him: he thunder'd down ſtairs, took Horſe, whipping and ſpurring without having the Courage to look behind him, till he came home, and there with ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt ſtammerings, delivered the ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed dreadful News of his young Maſter's fatal Diſaſter teſtified under his own Hand: but when the Truth of the bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs came out, it proved to be only the Devil Tavern, where he was recreating himſelf with ſome Friends.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="72" type="jest">
               <pb n="55" facs="tcp:35696:37" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>72.</head>
               <p>A Country Lawyer being in years, yet, upon a ſecond Marriage, taking a brisk young Wife, ſhe made many dumb ſigns to inveigle his Clerk to her Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>braces<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> who, for a while, did not, or would not underſtand them: but grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing gameſome, ſhe perſecuted him ſo at laſt, that by tickling, and other Love-tricks he could not write in his Desk for her. Wheroupon, he made a mark with Chalk, about two yards diſtance, upon the floor, telling her, That if ſhe came over it, he would lay her down and ruffle her to ſome purpoſe. Will you ſo, <hi>(ſaid ſhe,)</hi> I'll venture that. Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on which, ſeeing but too plainly what ſhe wou'd be at, he took her in his arms, and threw her upon the bed: where, as to what they did, we drew the curtain. A little Boy, that cou'd but juſt ſpeak, ſaw this paſſage; and the Lawyer com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing home, and about to ſtep over the chalk, he catch'd hold of him, crying, Oh, Father! Father! if you ſtep over the chalk the Clerk will take you and throw you on the bed, and then lye upon you a
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:35696:38" rendition="simple:additions"/>great while, as he did upon my Mother. By this we ſee, Children and Fools tell truth.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="73" type="jest">
               <head>73.</head>
               <p>A Woman, playing not only falſe with her husband, but with her Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant, admitted more to her Embraces: ſo that one coming ſuddenly, before ſhe cou'd diſmiſs the other, ſhe made the firſt get upon the Beds Teaſter, whil'ſt ſhe entertain'd the ſecond; but hearing her Husband's tread, coming up ſtairs, ſhe thruſt him under the bed. The Husband, by the heat and confuſion ſhe was in, the rumpling of her cloaths, and the like, ſmelling a Rat, commanded her to tell him who had been there. She ſolemnly proteſted, No body. But he urging it further, ſhe, with up lifted hands, proteſted again, ſaying, There's One adove knows all. The Fellow on the Teaſter thinking ſhe had purpoſely betray'd him, put out his Head, all hung with Cobwebs, and ſaid, There's one underneath the Bed knows as much as I: Whereupon, the other crept out, all rowled in the Duſt. She ſeeing now,
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:35696:38" rendition="simple:additions"/>it was in vain to deny it, fell upon her knees; and begg'd pardon. Which the good-natur'd Cuckold granted her, ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king her Word for her future Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſty.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="74" type="jest">
               <head>74.</head>
               <p>A grave, old Country Blade coming before a Judge, and taking his Oath in a Cauſe, he was bid to have a care what he ſwore, leſt he went to the Devil: I fear not that, <hi>(reply'd he, by way of retort,)</hi> for I have given him my eldeſt Son, and he ought to be contented with one out of a Family. How's that, <hi>(ſays the Judge,)</hi> pray explain your ſelf. Why truly, I have made him a Lawye, and you know the Devil was a Lawyer from the beginning. A Lyar you mean, <hi>(ſaid the other.)</hi> I know not <hi>(reply'd he)</hi> what diſtinction there may be made in <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> but I'm ſure, by ſad Experience, we in the Country know no difference between a Lawyer and a Lyar.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="75" type="jest">
               <pb n="58" facs="tcp:35696:39" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>75.</head>
               <p>A French-men coming to plead at the Barr, in a Cauſe, and ſpeaking broken Engliſh, came at laſt to citing of Caſes: Now, my Lord <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving gone thus far, I'll <hi>ſhite</hi> you ſome Caſes to prove it. Then I <hi>ſhite</hi> you the Firſt Caſe; now I <hi>ſhite</hi> you a Second: Having cited theſe two, Now <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> I will <hi>ſhite</hi> you a <hi>Turd.</hi> Then ſaid the Judge, joakingly, I hope you will have the manners to withdraw, and not do it openly in the Court, before all this Company, eſpecially in hot Weathor. This non-plus'd Monſieur, and put him beſide his Caſes, whil'ſt the People found matter for laughter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="76" type="jest">
               <head>76.</head>
               <p>An old Blade with a great Beard, ſtanding near a Carr-Horſe, the Horſe taking his Beard for a bottle of Hay, cry'd Whehee, and ſnap'd at it; which made the old Man give ſuch a leap back, that he ſtumbled and fell in the Kennel: when getting up, he fell to
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:35696:39"/>cudgelling the Horſe, and in a great rage, cry'd out, You plaguy Toad, who made you a Barber, that you muſt at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt to ſhave me, with a pox t'yee?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="77" type="jest">
               <head>77.</head>
               <p>A Water-man having taken divers into his Boat, and they not ſitting in equal ballance, cry'd, as is uſual, Pray, Gentlemen, trim the Boat. Whereat, a Barber being one in company, ſtar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted up and cry'd, You Whore's-bird! How came you to know that I am a Barber?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="78" type="jest">
               <head>78.</head>
               <p>A humor ſome Fop taking pleaſure to be laugh'd at, thinking, upon that ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, that his Diſcourſe was very plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing: A brisk Lady told him, Truly, Sir, you have a tickling Fancy; and ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther that want being the ſubject of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſion you will court your own Sha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow to flout yee.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="79" type="jest">
               <pb n="60" facs="tcp:35696:40" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>79.</head>
               <p>A Sailor having been a three-years Voyage, his Wife came to welcome him home, with a Kinchin of about half a year old in her arms: At the fight of which he grew cruſty, ſaying, He thought ſhe had been an honeſter Woman, than to have ſerv'd him ſuch a trick? Why <hi>(Reply'd ſhe)</hi> did you force me to do it, by ſtaying longer that your Promiſe? I could not help that, <hi>(ſaid he.)</hi> Nor could I this, <hi>(ſaid ſhe:)</hi> For one night leaving my Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber-door open, between ſleep and 'wake, I found my ſelf boarded a-ſtern, and thought it had been thee, my Dear, that came ſtealing in to ſurprize me; but being more vigorouſly attack'd than uſual, I ſomething doubted, and ſaid ſoftly to my ſelf, <hi>I pray God it be John!</hi> Well <hi>(ſaid he)</hi> if it happen'd againſt thy Will, I freely forgive thee: come, let's kiſs and be Friends; but be ſure to be more cautious how you leave your Door open another time, for this is a ſlippery world we live in, I muſt tell you that.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="80" type="jest">
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:35696:40" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>80.</head>
               <p>A French man coming to a houſe, had a Diſh dreſs'd after the Gallick Mode; but ſome Spice being wanting, he call'd, in the abſence of the Miſtreſs, to a Country Wench, that was newly come thither as a Servant, to take the Diſh, and put ſome <hi>Pice</hi> in it, (that being the French pronunciation, in broken Engliſh, for Spice.) The Wench ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gining he bid her piſs in it, ſet her flood<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate open, and <hi>pic'd</hi> it to the purpoſe, and ſo returned it. But he ſeeing no Spice, ſtill call'd for ſome, not minding any thing elſe. When the Miſtreſs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in, ſaid, How now, why don't you give the gentleman what he asks for? Indeed, Madam, ſaid ſhe, I have; for I piſs'd as much as I cou'd, and he is ſo unreaſonable, as not to be contented with it</p>
            </div>
            <div n="81" type="jest">
               <head>81.</head>
               <p>A young Widow having buried an old Husband, pretends ſo great a love to his Memory, that ſhe had his Image
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:35696:41" rendition="simple:additions"/>carv'd, and laid by her Side every Night; which ſhe kiſſed and embraced, vowing perperual Widow-hood. But her Maid thinking this but Hypocriſie, brib'd by a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> young Gallant, ſuffered him to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> place of the Image, as a more <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> fellow for a brisk Woman: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> him unwittingly the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> but e're Morning, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o far <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> him: but the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> want of Billets to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſaid, Burn old <hi>Simon,</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>, (ſo ſhe call'd the Image, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Husband's Name,) for now I have done with him, and got a better Bed-fellow.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="82" type="jest">
               <head>82.</head>
               <p>A Widow returning from the burial of her Husband, all in Tears; you muſt know, an officious Neighbour offered her his Service, to hand her home; which ſhe accepted, and by the way, began a needleſs Oration to comfort her; telling her withal, That he was a Widower, and at her devotion. Indeed
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:35696:41" rendition="simple:additions"/>Sir, <hi>ſaid ſhe</hi>) I thank you for your kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, but it is too late to make ſuch a Proffer; had you done it a day ſooner, I ſhould have accepted it, but I was married privately this Morning, as not being able to lye longer alone, for fear of Spirits.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="83" type="jest">
               <head>83.</head>
               <p>An old Beldam being carry'd before the Juſtice, for keeping a Bawdy houſe, endeavoured to deny and excuſe it: How, Huſwife! <hi>ſays the Juſtice,</hi> have you the impudence to deny it? I know you do keep a Bawdy-houſe, and I'll maintain it. At this the old Woman, miſtaking his meaning, took heart, and dropping him a Court'ſie, ſaid, I thank your Worſhip a hundred times, I want ſuch good Cuſtomers and Supporters as you, to recover my great decay of Trade, or I ſhall be ruin'd, as Times goe. At this the Juſtice bluſh'd, and the People laugh'd; yet, for the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit's ſake, remitted her Puniſhment.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="84" type="jest">
               <pb n="64" facs="tcp:35696:42"/>
               <head>84.</head>
               <p>A Country Gentleman being a Juſtice of Peace, having been highly offended by his Footman, reſolv'd to have him corrected, without giving himſelf the trouble of doing it; and therefore writ a Letter to the Keeper of the <hi>Bride well,</hi> That he ſhould, upon the receit, take the Bearer of it, and give him ſeverely the Correction of the Houſe. This Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter he gave him to carry, and bring a ſpeedy Anſwer back. Yet by the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, miſtruſting ſome miſchief, came to an Ale-houſe, where he ſound aluſty Tinker half drunk, and for Two Pots got him to carry it. The <hi>Bridewell</hi>-man, upon firſt ſight, cauſed him to be ſtripp'd, ſaying, How durſt you, Sirrah, abuſe ſo worthy a Gentleman? Upon this, he deny'd he knew him, and told where he had the Letter. But all would not do, till he had Forty Laſhes; and then being let looſe, ran to find out and kill the Fellow that had put the trick upon him: But Peell-garlick, upon no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice, was rubb'd off; and telling his Maſter how he had trick'd the Tinker, obtain'd his Pardon.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="85" type="jest">
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:35696:42"/>
               <head>85.</head>
               <p>A Fellow, comically diſpos'd, having gotten a great many Horns in a Basket, cryed, <hi>New Furniture, Rare Furniture.</hi> Whereupon, a grave Citizen admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring what it ſhould be, deſir'd to ſee it; and thereupon ſaid, Why, you cox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>combly Fool, think you any one is ſo mad, to buy ſuch Ware? Yes, marry, I do, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> for though you are fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd, there are many, as wiſe as your ſelf, that may have occaſion for them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="86" type="jest">
               <head>86.</head>
               <p>A Fellow running along the ſtreet, half out of breath, crying, <hi>Fire! Fire!</hi> Nay, ſaid the People, you had better cry Water, for it ſeems there is too much Fire already.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="87" type="jest">
               <head>87.</head>
               <p>A Man having bought a pair of Bucks-Horns, his Wife asked him, what he meant to do with them? Oh, <hi>ſays he,</hi> hang my Hat on them. And why
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:35696:43"/>upon Horns. Husband? you might have done that, and have kept it upon your Head.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="88" type="jest">
               <head>88.</head>
               <p>A Bailiff clapping a Man on the Shoulder, ſaid, <hi>I Arreſt you, Sir, for a Horſe,</hi> (meaning, for the Money he ow'd for a Horſe.) Why, <hi>reply'd the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant,</hi> thou errant Coxcomb, thou art not, certainly, ſuch a Fool as thou ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keſt thy ſelf? Pray look upon me again: What likeneſs can you ſee, that you ſhould be ſo blockheaded, as to take me for a Horſe? Then tripping up his heels, ſaid, However, I'll ſhew you a Horſe-trick; and after giving him two or three kicks, left him in the Kennel, and ſo march'd off.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="89" type="jest">
               <head>89.</head>
               <p>At a French Univerſity, they admit the Degree of <hi>Doclor</hi> to be taken, in lieu of a Summ of Money to ſupply certain Colleges, without conſide4ing their Learning and Abilities. One of which thinking to punn upon the place, ſaid,
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:35696:43" rendition="simple:additions"/>merrily, that ſince he was made a Doctor, he was willing his Horſe might <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e commenced too, that being far from great Towns, where many times he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>net with Patients, he need not, having <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is Horſe with him, be at the trouble to ſend for another Phyſician, upon any thing that required a Conſult. That may be done, <hi>ſaid the Prolocuter;</hi> for it is no ſuch difficulty for us who have made an Aſs a Doctor, to make an Horſe one likewiſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="90" type="jest">
               <head>90.</head>
               <p>A brisk Widow having an Inn, bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Sign of the <hi>Maiden-Head,</hi> left her as a Dowry; but there being a dofective Title, ſhe was Ejected: wherefore, in a pitiful Tone, ſhe ſaid, Now I find there's Law, even againſt keeping of Maiden-heads, for I have loſt this Mai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den-head by Law. Says one to her, Prithee, tell me, Did you take ſo on, when you loſt your other Maiden-head? No, indeed, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> I had rather have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>oſt that twenty times over; for the Fruits of that Maiden-head I can ſhew ſtill, but this is gone from me for ever.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="91" type="jest">
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:35696:44" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>91.</head>
               <p>A Man being to get Goffips for the Chriſtning of his Wife's Child, told her, He had pitch'd upon ſuch a One. who, by the Neighbours, was thought to be more than ordinarily familiar with her. At which, lifting up her Hands, ſhe cry'd out, O the Father! that you ſhou'd think of him!</p>
            </div>
            <div n="92" type="jest">
               <head>92.</head>
               <p>A Shentleman of <hi>Wales,</hi> ſeeing one with a large Pomkin in his hand, ſaid, <hi>Was beſeech hur, tell hur what has hur got there?</hi> Why, a Mare's Egg, you Fool you, (reply'd the other.) <hi>And was hur get a Coult out of it, was think hur?</hi> Yes, (reply'd the other) <hi>Then hur was want one, if hur will ſell hur one?</hi> Yes, (ſaid the other.) <hi>Then, Cot, Cot, bur will give hur a Groat for it?</hi> Content, (ſaid the other.) So the Money was laid down, and Pomkin deliver'd, and the Welſh-man trudg'd up a Hill with it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> but the Stalk breaking, it fell; and rowling down, ſtruck againſt a Buſh,
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:35696:44" rendition="simple:additions"/>out of which ſtarted a Hare; which the Cambrio. Britain ſeeing, and thinking his Mare's Egg had brought forth, run after her, crying, <hi>Stop hur Colt, ſtop bur Colt;</hi> but Puſs not minding his Clamour, kept on her way, and the Pomkin roul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into the Thicket, lay undiſcove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red; ſo that to his great fretting and diſappointment, he went home diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tented without either, to tell the ſtrange Adventure.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="93" type="jest">
               <head>93.</head>
               <p>A Phyſitian having ſent for a Farrier, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o blood and drench his Horſe, and of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering him Money; No, <hi>ſays the Farrier,</hi> we are Brothers in our Practice, and muſt take no Fees of one another, only my deſire is, That when I have occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for you, you would deal as ſincere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly by me, as I have done by your Horſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="94" type="jest">
               <head>94.</head>
               <p>A young Gentlewoman, of great For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune, being Married, and the firſt and ſecond Year, no Child in likelyhood, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>er Mother made ſtrict Inquiry, where
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:35696:45"/>the Defect lay; and upon her diſcove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, after many bluſhings, and heſitations, that it was in the Husband, ſhe prevail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> her to ſue out a Divorce: And the young Lady coming to ſhew he<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Reaſons, deſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ed, for Modeſty's ſake, ſhe might wri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e them, which was al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed; and at<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>empting it, being told there was no Ink in her Pen, Why tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> that is my Caſt, and you have ſaved me the Labour, by finding out what I deſigned to write.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="95" type="jest">
               <head>95.</head>
               <p>A drunken Tinker, having told, in a dograding way, That he had ofter worked at ſuch a Gentleman's Houſe but that he kept ſuch a penurious watch over his Servants, they durſt not give him a d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>aught of Drink. The Gentle<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> man being diſpleaſed at this, ordered <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Butt of Stout, that ſtood an end, t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> have the upper Head taken out, and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiry to be made for this ſmutty Meta<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> monger, to come and mend ſome Cop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers; and being found, accordingly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> came: when being lead into the Celar, Two luſty Fellows ſtript him, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="71" facs="tcp:35696:45"/>ſet <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> the Liquor up to the Chin; then came the Gentleman with his drawb <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>as if in an angry mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d,</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> you have thus diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graced <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Butt, or off goes your <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ead the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> gegged his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ardon, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> do) for ſeeing you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> have at you; then <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> over the Top of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> the Tinker, to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>void the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> and having often compelled <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> till almoſt drowned in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> he bid him beware how he complaited for Liquor at his Houſe another time. Nay, truly Sir, <hi>ſaid he.</hi> I never will; for now I have had too much.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="96" type="jest">
               <head>96.</head>
               <p>A young Gentlewoman having new<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly buried, her Husband, who left her a conſiderable Eſtate, the Cobler of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> on this, reſolving to try his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>, put on his Roaſt-meat Cloaths, and deſired to ſpeak with her about Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs, that nearly concerned her Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon; and with ſome difficulty, being ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, ſay'd, Madam, underſtanding
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:35696:46"/>you are a Widow, and I a widower, I come to offer my Service to you: For what? <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> Why, in good troth <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd he</hi>) to make you a Husband. A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way filthy Fellow! <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> get you gone, or I ſhall call up my Servants to kick you down Stairs for your Impu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence. Nay Madam, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> be not Angry, for I cou'd but ask you, and if you won't, another will.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="97" type="jest">
               <head>97.</head>
               <p>Some married Perſons going by the place, where the Royal Oak Lottery was kept, a Motion was made, to go in and try their Luck: <hi>ſays one,</hi> None but Cuckolds have any at Gaming; <hi>ſays his Wife,</hi> However, Husband try, for I am confident you cannot miſs of a good Chance.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="98" type="jest">
               <head>98.</head>
               <p>A ſoft headed Gentleman, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Eſtate, having his Child put to Nurſe by the order of his Wife, in his Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence, would needs go to ſee how i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> throve; and finding the Nurſe to be a
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:35696:46"/>married Woman, grew out of humour, and ſaid, It was ſit a Virgin, Chamber-Maid Nurſes, and not Marry'd Nurſes, ſhould have the ſuckling of Gentlemens Children; for they conſequently have the beſt Milk: giving his Reaſon, That Virgin-Milk muſt be as pure as Virgin-Honey, or Pullets Eggs: And ſuch a one he would provide. Alas, Sir, ſaid ſhe, there are none ſuch to be ſound amongſt us ſimple People in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey; but if you go to the <hi>Intelligence Offices</hi> in <hi>London,</hi> you may have a Wet-Chamber-Maid recommended to you, but I hardly believe you will find a Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin there that gives ſuck.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="99" type="jest">
               <head>99.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman who had a monſtrous great Noſe, coming often to Dine at a Nobleman's who kept a Fool, the Fool would <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſtaring and fleering at <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>, See there! See there! <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Noſe that Man has! Which ſometimes occaſioned laughter in the Company, but made the Owner of the Noſe fret, though he could not tell how to help himſelf. His Buſineſs lying fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:35696:47"/>here, one day met the Fool privately, and told him, He would give him Sixpence, if he'd promiſe to twit him with his great Noſe no more. The Fool promiſed he would be his Friend in it, and ſo they parted. But the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman ſitting at Dinner, when time came, as uſual, in comes the Fool, and thinking to do the Gentleman a Cour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tene, by retracting what he had ſaid, cry'd out, That Man has no Noſe at all! No Noſe at all! No Noſe at all! and ſo he continued bawling; which occaſion'd more laughter than before.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="100" type="jest">
               <head>100.</head>
               <p>Theſe ſort of Fools are ſometime very malicious, and bloodily revenge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, for any Aff<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>onts they receive: A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> a poor Fellow, a Carpenter, once ſadly experienced, who having anger'd a No<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>bleman's Fool, by throwing Water i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> his Face, he kept his Reſentments t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> himſelf, but watched an Opportunity. The Man not thinking any harm, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Dinnor, it being het Weather, la<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> at his length, upon a Log, a-ſleep, wit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> his Axe by him; with which the Foo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="75" facs="tcp:35696:47"/>being a ſturdy Fellow, with one ſtrong blow ſtruck off his Head, and hid it in the Saw duſt: Then running in a doors, he fell into a fit of laughter, till he dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel'd again: And being ask'd why he did ſo? Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> the braveſt funn that ever you heard of. What is that, <hi>Jack, ſaid one of the Servants?</hi> Why, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> I laugh to think, when the Carpenter wakes, how like a Fool he'll look without his Head, and loſe his Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ternoon's work, to find it out where I have hid it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="101" type="jest">
               <head>101.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow, ditching by the Way-ſide, happen'd, as ſome Perſons were riding along, to ſee a Hundred Pound Bag drop out of a Portmantua; which he carefully took up and carry'd to his Wife, whithout opening. She knowing him to be a ſoft-headed Fellow, and fearing he would diſcover it, threw it aſide, ſaying, What d'yee bring this Pudding bag of Dirt to me for? you might have as well have ſtopp'd a gap with it. Truly, Sweet-heart, <hi>ſays he,</hi> I found it, and thought it might have
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:35696:48"/>been worth ſomething; but if it ben't, it is but my labour loſt. Come, Come, <hi>ſays ſhe,</hi> you are ſimple, and muſt go to School, to learn to Read and Write, and then you may get into a better Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment. E'en what you will, Sweet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heart, <hi>ſaid he;</hi> and ſo the old Blade was ſent to learn his Horn-book; till by the Childrens laughing at him, he grew weary of it, and returned to his former Buſineſs. The Parties who had loſt the Money, upon their return from <hi>London,</hi> enquired all along the Road, if any ſuch Bag was taken up; and remembring they had ſeen this Man at work, asked him. Who anſwered, Yes; and his Wiſe had it at home. So home they went with him: But the woman ſtifly deny'd it, ſaying, He was fooliſh and phrenſical, and ſometimes talk'd idly, and therefore they ought not to give cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit to what he ſaid. But they inſiſting on it, ſhe deſir'd them to ask him when it was that he ſound it? Why, <hi>reply'd he</hi> among all the days of the year, I very well remember, it was the day before I firſt went to School. At this they fell a laughing, and thinking indeed he was crack-brain'd, departed, ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:35696:48"/>with what the Woman had told them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="102" type="jest">
               <head>102.</head>
               <p>A Uſurer having loſt an Hundred Pounds, put out Ten Pounds Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward for any that ſhould bring it him. A tender-conſcienc'd Man finding it, brought it to him, demanding the T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Pounds. Then, to baffle him, he al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg'd, there was a Hundred and Ten Pounds in the Bag, when loſt; but up on breaking-open the Seal, there ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear'd no more than an Hundred. The Man Arreſted him for his Promiſe; and it coming to be Try'd before a Judge of <hi>Niſi Prius,</hi> it appearing the Seal had not been broken-open, nor the Bag ripp'd, ſays the Judge to the Defendant, The Bag you loſt had a Hundred and Ten Pounds in it, you ſay? Yes, My Lord, <hi>ſaid he.</hi> Then, <hi>reply'd the Judge,</hi> ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Evidence given in Court, this cannot be your Money, for here was but a Hundred Pounds; therefore the Plaintiff muſt keep it till the true Owner comes, and you muſt look for your Hundred and Ten Pounds where you can find it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="103" type="jest">
               <pb n="78" facs="tcp:35696:49" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>103.</head>
               <p>A weighty Cauſe coming before a corrupt Judge, he took Bribes on both Sides: One gave him a Coach, and the other a pair of fine Horſes; ſo that he that gave the Horſes, had the Cauſe: Oh, Coach! <hi>then ſaid the other,</hi> thou art gone the wrong way! <hi>Said the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant,</hi> How could you expect otherwiſe? for you might well think, where my Hor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes draw, your Coach muſt follow.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="104" type="jest">
               <head>104.</head>
               <p>A fooliſh Aft<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ologer being Jealous of his Wiſe, not without reaſon, reſolv'd to try, by his Art, whether he was a Cuckold, or no. Of which her Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant hearing, ſent him theſe Lines:
<q>
                     <l>Star-gazing Fool! thou from the Signs would'ſt ſee,</l>
                     <l>And Planets Face, what thy Wife's Deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings be!</l>
                     <l>She does her Work below, where ne'er Sun pries;</l>
                     <l>And though ſhe's light, ſhe mounts not to the Skies;</l>
                     <pb n="79" facs="tcp:35696:49"/>
                     <l>'Cauſe ſhe's kept down by me. If in the Sphere,</l>
                     <l>Thou <hi>Venus</hi> ſee, thou think<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ſt thy Wiſe is there:</l>
                     <l>Or if the <hi>Bull,</hi> or <hi>Aries,</hi> thou do'ſt ſee,</l>
                     <l>Thou think'ſt they point their Horns direck at thee.</l>
                     <l>Fool! keep at home, while thou abroad do'ſt go,</l>
                     <l>In Imitation, thy Wife's Legs do ſo:</l>
                     <l>And when thou gazeſt in the Skies, to know</l>
                     <l>Her Works, ſhe do's ev'n what ſhe pleaſe below.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="105" type="jest">
               <head>105.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman whoſe Miſtreſs, with Vows and Proteſtations, had affur'd him a laſting Love and Conſtancy: yet finding, through her Diſſimulation, that ſhe was fickle and wavering; to ſhew the little Credit he gave to her Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtations, wrote theſe Lines:
<q>
                     <l>My Miſtreſs ſaith, She'll marry none but me,</l>
                     <l>Tho' Jove himſelf ſhould force her unto it:</l>
                     <l>But Womens Words unto their Lovers, be</l>
                     <l>So firm, they may in Wind or Waves be writ.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="106" type="jest">
               <pb n="80" facs="tcp:35696:50" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>106.</head>
               <p>Two Fellows reeling, drunk, fell into a Gravel-Pit; and imagining they fell into the Trap-door of a Cellar, one cry'd, Ho! <hi>Jack!</hi> where are you? Why, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I am ſearching about to find the Taps, that I may let all the Drink out. That's well done, <hi>ſays t'other;</hi> and I am clambering up, to pull down the Sign: We'll teach 'em to leave their Cellar-door open, at this time of Night, to catch Travellers.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="107" type="jest">
               <head>107.</head>
               <p>A Country 'Squire coming up to Town, and being at a Tavern among his Acquaintance, and complained he had had his Pocket pick'd in a Crowd, as he came along. Says the Country Blade, I defie any one to pick mine; for I always carry my Hands in 'em. I'll wager a Guinea, to be ſpent, <hi>ſays another,</hi> that you ſhall not go to <hi>Smith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field-Rounds,</hi> but you ſhall loſe your Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger. Done, <hi>ſaid he.</hi> And ſo, while they drunk about, the Party ſent for
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:35696:50"/>Two notable Proficients in the Myſtery of Diving and Sharping, gave 'em a ſight of our Country 'Squire, told them the way he was to go, and that he pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed to carry in his Mouth a Broad-Piece of Gold, mark'd with a <hi>(W.)</hi> This will be hard to get: however, <hi>ſaid they,</hi> we'll try our Skill: and ſo being promiſed a Crown, and Indemp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>y, they watch'd hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> ſetting out and followed him. Coming to the <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>,</hi> while he flood looking about <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> one of them pull'd out a Handker<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="5 letters">
                     <desc>•••••</desc>
                  </gap> and, as by chan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> ſcatter'd ſome <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> and Farthings: Thereupon, crying <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> undone, if they ſtood not by him to prevent a Scramble! Our Country<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, among the reſt, was buſie, and pick'd up ſome; which he gave him Then his Comrade asked him if he had all? No indeed, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I want a Broad-piece of Gold, that I highly prize, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe it was given me by my Grand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mother, upon her Death bead. Why, <hi>ſaid the other,</hi> I ſaw this Country-man put it into his Mouth. Then ſaid he, if it be mine, it is mark'd with a <hi>(W.)</hi> The Country 'Squire deny'd not that he had ſuch a Piece, but ſaid it was his
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:35696:51"/>own: however, the Rabble gathering about him, and crying out, Knock him on the Head, for a Rogue! he was forc'd to deliver it. So away the two Sharpers went, and deliver'd it to the Party that had ſet them at work; who gave them the promis'd Reward. At laſt, in came our country Blade very melancholy, owned his Wager loſt, and ſaid, He fear'd, if he ſtay'd long in <hi>London,</hi> he ſhould have his Teeth ſtole out of his Head, at this rate: therefore he would down into the Country again, where there was no Cheating but among Great Men and Jockeys at Horſe-Races, and Ladies at Cards.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="108" type="jest">
               <head>108.</head>
               <p>One having loſt a Watch, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into the Company of an arch Poet, upon telling his lamentable Diſaſter, One deſir'd a Verſe or two to be made on it, as a <hi>Memento</hi> to others: Which run thus:
<q>
                     <l>All you that Watches have, this do,</l>
                     <l>Pocket your Watch, and watch your Pocket too.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="109" type="jest">
               <pb n="83" facs="tcp:35696:51" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>109.</head>
               <p>One following a Gentlewoman, and paſſing her, turn'd back to look in her Face, and ſaid, Madam, you are ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Handſome. I wiſh, Sir, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> without wronging my Judgement, I could return you the like Complement. A Pox take your Scruples! <hi>reply'd he;</hi> Why can't you tell a Lye for me, as well as I have told one for you?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="110" type="jest">
               <head>110.</head>
               <p>A Gentlewoman deſiring to know of a Phyſitian, Whether the Milk of a Cow might not do as well as Aſſes Milk, ſo much cry'd up, upon that account? Truly, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> every thing ought to have Milk of its Kind; my Patients ought to have Affes Milk: but if any other Doctor has Calves to his Patients, Cows Milk is proper.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="111" type="jest">
               <head>111.</head>
               <p>A noted Bawd being ſent to <hi>Bridewell,</hi> for occaſioning the debauchery of a
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:35696:52"/>young Gentlewoman, by enticing her to the laſcivious Embraces of a Spark, for a Summ of Money, ſhe fell ſick and died there, leaving much Wealth behind her, ordering, by her Laſt Will, Five Guinea's for a Funeral Sermon; in the Concluſion of which, the Miniſter was to give her a good Character. But not knowing what to ſay of her who had lead ſo leud a Life, leſt he ſhould be ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter'd upon, as one of her Cuſtomers, he got a Stranger to Preach: Who, after <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſaid, It is, I doubt not, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected, but that I ſhould ſay ſomething in behalf of the Party deceaſed: All that can be ſaid, is, She was Born well, Brought-up well, Liv'd well, and Dy'd well: being born at <hi>shadwell,</hi> brought-up at <hi>Camberwell,</hi> living a Houſe-keeper at <hi>Clerkenwell;</hi> and, laſtly, my Beloved, dying in <hi>Bridewell.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="112" type="jest">
               <head>112.</head>
               <p>An ignorant Country Lad being cited, among the reſt of the Pariſh-Children, upon a Viſitation, to be Catechized; after ſome othee had anſwered, the Commandments came to his turn to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peat:
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:35696:52" rendition="simple:additions"/>And being asked, how many there were? he ſtood gaping, as if he had heard Dutch ſpoken. What! <hi>ſaid the Miniſter,</hi> Can a Fellow of your Age be ignorant of this Queſtion? I though you had known them, and kept them too? No indeed, <hi>reply'd be, very ſeriouſly,</hi> I never kept any thing in my life, but my Father's Sheep.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="113" type="jest">
               <head>113.</head>
               <p>A Country Woman having ſent her Son with a Basket of Medlers, to a Lady that was her Landlady; he, though very clowniſh, thought, however, to beſtow a Complement upon ſo fine a Woman, at the delivery, ſaid, Forſooth, my Mother has ſent you a whole Peck of Open-Arſes; but let me tell you, by the way, if you don't keep them till they are as rotten as a Turd, they will not be worth a Fart. The Lady ſmiling at his Manners, gave him a Shilling. Soon after, the Mother came with her Rent; and being ſat at Dinner, the Lady was telling her what a pretty Boy ſhe had, but withal, very Clowniſh, and told her likewiſe what he had ſaid. Was he ſo
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:35696:53"/>Unmannerly, notwithſtanding the good Breeding I have beſtow'd on my ſelf, (ſays the Woman, ſtarting up in a Rage,) Ne'er ſtir! Madam, if I don't go home and whip the Raſcal till he beſhits him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf agen! This turn'd ſome ſqueamiſh Stomachs; but the Lady ſmiling at it, ſaid, No, No, you ſhall not beat him; for I ſee he was no better taught.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="114" type="jest">
               <head>114.</head>
               <p>A Lady having caſt a Perſon at Law, who contended with her for great a part of her Eſtate, in Joy for her Succeſs, invited her Tenants to a ſplendid Dinner; and telling them the cauſe of it, ſaid, You ſee, my honeſt Neighbours, my Right has, at laſt, taken place, and my Adverſary is fruſtrated of his unjuſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectations. Upon this, up ſtarts a blunt Country, and thinking to paſs a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plement, ſaid, Madam, i always thought he took the wrong Sow by the Ear, when he meddl'd with your Lady<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="115" type="jest">
               <pb n="87" facs="tcp:35696:53" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>115.</head>
               <p>Some Gentlemen coming into an Inn, in <hi>London,</hi> in cold Weather, and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiving the Carriers and Porters had wedged in the Fire, that they could not come at it; One wink'd at the Hoſtler, and bid him fetch Half of Peck of Oyſters, and give them to his Horſe. At this ſome ſtar'd, and others laugh'd. Why, Good Fellows, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> if you knew what kind of Horſe mine it, you would not think it ſtrange; for he's a Sea-Horſe, and only feeds upon Shell-Fiſh. At this they all ſtart up, and run to ſee him, as ſome ſtrange Wonder; whil'ſt the Gentlemen and his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panions poſſeſſed their warm Places, and left them in the Cold, to fret at their folly, in being ſo dexterouſly out-witted.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="116" type="jest">
               <head>116.</head>
               <p>A Man that had marry'd a bitter ſcolding Wife, that worry'd him almoſt out of his Life, being frighted one Even<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, as he was coming home, by a
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:35696:54" rendition="simple:additions"/>Phantom, or Spirit, which, as it drew nigher, put him into a ſweating and trembling Condition, Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> if thou art a Good Spirit, thou wilt do poor Mortals no Injury; but if thou art a Bad One, and belongeſt to the Devil, there is all the reaſon in the world thou ſhould'ſt ſpare me, becauſe I am ſo nearly related to thy Maſter, as having but newly marry'd his Siſter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="117" type="jest">
               <head>117.</head>
               <p>A Fellow ſuſpecting himſelf to be a Cuckold, reſolved, by a Stratagem, to get Confeſſion of it from his Wife; and thereupon getting a great many Coc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s Spurs, with ſome Glew, demanded the Queſtion? But ſhe deny'd it. Well, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> for all this, I know I am ſo; and I have been with a Cunning-Man about it, and he has found out, that you have play'd falſe with me once, and ſee here thereupon a Horn riſen on my Fore-head; and he tells me, next time I come. he will raiſe as many Horns, by his Art, to upbraid you, as the times you have been falſe to my Bed. O dear Husband! <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> don't go to him no
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:35696:54" rendition="simple:additions"/>more, leſt you become a Monſter all over.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="118" type="jest">
               <head>118.</head>
               <p>An old Woman, of Fourſcore, having marry'd a luſty Fellow of Five and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; and he uſing her ſcurvily, which made her crawl to a Juſtice's, to make her Complaint, and get a Warrant, in order to Bind him over to his Good-behaviour: Where ſhe was reproved, for being ſo fooliſh to marry in her Old Age, when ſhe ought to have minded better things, as having one Foot in the Grave. What! <hi>reply'd ſhe, very angrily,</hi> wou'd you have me turn Whore?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="119" type="jest">
               <head>119.</head>
               <p>A Fellow having Indicted a Butcher of <hi>Picadilly,</hi> at the <hi>Old-Baily,</hi> for ſtealing his Sow, produced the Sow's Head, which was found in his Powdering-Tub, as an Evidence of the Fact. Says the Court, did you ſhew this to any body, as ſoon as you found it? Yes, (ſays the Fellow, miſtaking by ſpeaking too ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerly, I carry'd the Juſtice's Head be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:35696:55" rendition="simple:additions"/>the Sow, and there the Priſoner confeſs'd the Fact.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="120" type="jest">
               <head>120.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow driving a Team, and the Fore-horſe being very ſat, the reſt lean, two Lawyers overtaking him, one ſaid to the other, let us joak upon this Fellow? A Match (ſaid the other.) Good Fellow, <hi>ſays the former,</hi> what is the reaſon that your Fore-Horſe is ſo plum, and full of fleſh, and all the reſt are of <hi>Pharaoh</hi>'s lean Kine? O, Sir. <hi>ſays he,</hi> he is the Lawyer, and the reſt are the Clients.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="121" type="jest">
               <head>121.</head>
               <p>A Welſh-man having ſold a great Eſtate in the Mountains, and in the Val<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leys, came up to <hi>London</hi> with a full Purſe; and ſeeing a Gentleman give Five Pounds for a Hawk, cheapned and bought one at the ſame price, and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately rung off his Neck. And be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ask'd the Reaſon for ſo doing? He reply'd, <hi>Plut, was let bur Engliſh-men know hur was a Shentleman of</hi> Wales, <hi>and
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:35696:55" rendition="simple:additions"/>cou'd afford to eat as good a Bird as the beſt of 'em all.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="122" type="jest">
               <head>122.</head>
               <p>A Spark that lodg'd in a Houſe where there was a brisk Landlady, whoſe Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band was none of the ableſt in Perfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mance; he coming into her Chamber, one day, in the abſence of the Good-Man, ſaid, He hoped ſhe would be kind to him? Why, when, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> was I ever otherwiſe? Ay, but I mean, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> in another manner? Why, truly, this is the firſt time you ever ask'd me, and I ſhould be uncivil, to refuſe your firſt Requeſt. This coming briskneſs daſhed the Gallant out of countenance, and made him willing to be off agen, as at that time not well provided; and thinking, by this means to do it, ſaid, Madam, One thing I'll barr. What's that? <hi>ſaid ſhe.</hi> Why, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> That you ſhall not cry-out? Puh! <hi>reply'd ſhe,</hi> trouble not your ſelf about that; but if you barr any thing, barr the Door, to prevent a Surprize.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="123" type="jest">
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:35696:56" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>123.</head>
               <p>A Country Girl, newly come to a <hi>London</hi>-Service, looking over the Shoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of ſome that were at Cards; a Man that was hem'd in, ſaid, Prithee, Sweet-heart, go into the Yard and make. Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for me, for I can't get out. To which the harmleſs Wench ſimply reply'd, Truly, Sir I can't do it now; for I juſt made Water in the Back-Room: but when I have a Need agen, I'll do't for you, with all my heart.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="124" type="jest">
               <head>124.</head>
               <p>A luſty Country Laſs, gathering Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, venturing too far, and over-reach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing her ſelf, ſlipp'd her Hold, and dropt with her Legs between the Forks of a Bough; which ſtripp'd up her Cloaths, that ſhe hung naked to the navel, kick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and ſprawling, and crying out for Help. A Fellow that was Thraſhing, ran immediately to relieve her, ſetting the Ladder to that Bough: But as he was going up, what through fear, ſhame, and ſtruggling to unlooſe her ſelf, her
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:35696:56" rendition="simple:additions"/>Flood-gate burſt open, whil'ſt ſhe cry'd out, Don't look, <hi>Harry!</hi> Don't look, <hi>Harry!</hi> Zuz' and fut'! Look! quo'thee? Why, thou haſt ſo blinded me with Urine, that I can hardly find my way to thee.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="125" type="jest">
               <head>125.</head>
               <p>A Miller having a good quantity of Corn come to be Ground, in his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence; when he came home, with his Diſh in his Hand, demanded, who had taken Toll? That have I, ſaid the Wife: And I, ſaid the Boy: And I, ſaid the Maid. Well, ſaid he, I ſhall believe ne'er a Rogue nor Whore of you all: for this is ſuch a Lying Age, that a Man ought not to believe any thing but what he ſees which his own Eyes; therefore, to be upon ſure grounds, I'll take it my ſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="126" type="jest">
               <head>126.</head>
               <p>A Man and a Woman, after hot Words, falling, together by the Ears in the Street, a great Crowd was gathered about them: Among the reſt, an Old
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:35696:57" rendition="simple:additions"/>Woman crowded in, to know what was the occaſion of that Tumult? and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fir'd a man that ſtood by her, to inform her how it began? You're a Whore! <hi>ſays he:</hi> And you're a Rogue, <hi>reply'd ſhe,</hi> to call me Whore. Why, e'en ſo, Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> the Quarrel began.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="127" type="jest">
               <head>127.</head>
               <p>Two Women falling out in <hi>Kent-ſtreet,</hi> after many hard Words had paſs'd on both Sides, ſays one, You had not only a Great-Belly when you was Married, but have made your Husband a Cuckold divers times ſince. The Man, who was a Taylor, and at work in a Garret croſs the way, hearing this, could hold no longer, but put his Head out of the Window; and calling aloud. What's that ſhe ſays, Sweet-heart? Why, my Dear, <hi>reply'd his Wife,</hi> ſhe ſays you're a Cuckold. Do's ſhe ſo, <hi>ſaid he?</hi> Had ſhe call'd me Aſs, or Puppy, or any ſuch ſociable Creature, I cou'd have borne it; but this Reflexion is inſuffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable: therefore, Come up preſently; carry my beſt Cloak to the Broaker's, and pawn it for Ten Groats; I'll have
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:35696:57" rendition="simple:additions"/>a Warrant for her, and ruine her, what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever betides me.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="128" type="jest">
               <head>128.</head>
               <p>A Journey-man and the Man of the Houſe's Siſter being very intimate, had often private Converſation when the reſt were a bed; and one Night, among other gameſome Frollicks, a large Smock hanging upon the Line by the Fire, the Man handling it, ſaid, VVhoſe Shift is this, Mrs. <hi>Sarah?</hi> VVhy, 'tis mine, <hi>reply'd ſhe.</hi> Indeed, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> you are very extravagant; half the Holland would have ſerv'd. No indeed, <hi>reply'd ſhe,</hi> it would not; for it is never a whit to wide, as the Faſhion is now. VVhy, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I'll wager you a Treat of Ten Shilling, it is big enough for us both, if our Cloaths were off? Done! <hi>ſaid ſhe;</hi> and immediately they ſtripp'd. (it not being the firſt time they had been ſo, upon other Occaſions;) but forcibly thruſting their Arms ſtreight in the Sleeves, (tho' the Wager was yielded,) they could not get them out agen, but reſolved to tear one of the Sleeves upon a Tenter-hook belonging to the Shelf
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:35696:58"/>where the Pewter ſtood: in order to which, they got upon a Joynt-ſtool, and having faſten'd the Linnen, jumpt down, and pull'd after them the Shelf, and all the Pewter. This unlucky Accident very much furpriz'd 'em; and no leſs the Maſter, and the reſt of the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily, who imagining there were Thieves in the Houſe, arm'd themſelves accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly with Spits, Forks, Tongs, and ſuch like Weapons; the Maſter, as Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, marching in the Front, ſaying to the others, Come, Boys, be of good Courage, you know the old Saying, <hi>One honeſt Man is ſtouter than Ten Thieves;</hi> Come on, I ſay; for I queſtion not but we ſhall quickly oblige them to yield, when one they perceive our Courage and Reſolution. Thus marching down the Stairs, as reſolute as an Army of Soldiers at the beſieging of a City, upon the Promiſe of Free-Plunder, they ſearch'd firſt in one Room, then in another, ſtill meeting with nothing that might oppoſe them; but at length, coming into the Room where the Pewter was wont to ſtand, inſtead of taking the Game they hunted for, they were more ſurpriſed than before,
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:35696:58"/>at the ſight of this unexpected and ſeem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly monſtrous Object, not knowing what to make on't, conſidering they had unluckily put out the Candle in their ſtriving to get out of the Smock, but only they might diſcern ſomething all white, with Two Heads, and Four Legs moving upon the floor, by the ſmall light which the Fire gave them: This ſtruck ſuch a Terror upon them all, that none of 'em durſt attempt to approach nigh it. All this while our entangl'd Couple lay ſtrugling, and ſweating on the ground, not daring, through fear and ſhame, to make them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves known to their affrighted Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders: Till the Maſter of the Houſe, being more couragious than the reſt, boldly reſolv'd to diſcover what it was; and coming towards 'em, was about to ſtick the Spit which he had in his Hand thorough the Body of this ſuppoſed Monſter; but the Woman perceiving the up-lifting of his Hand, skreamed out, ſaying, Oh, Brother! Mercy! Mercy, for Heav'ns ſake1 it is I, it is I, your diſtreſſed Siſter, and unfortunate Journey-man, <hi>Richard,</hi> who innocently ſporting together, have
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:35696:59"/>moſt unhappily twined our ſelves in this manner; out of which it is impoſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible for us to get free, without ſome Aſſiſtance from your helping hand therefore, I beſeech you, as a tender Brother, have ſome Compaſſion for your miſerable Siſter, and her unhappy Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion, in the Condition we are now in, and our urmoſt Endeavours ſhall be, for the future, to retaliate your Kindneſs in the higheſt manner we ſhall ever be capable of performing; (the Fellow groaning and ſighing all the while, not ſpeaking one word for himſelf, but ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecting to be ſent immediately into the other World, for the Affront put upon his Maſter, in being ſo over-familiar with his Siſter.) Her Brother ſtarting, to hear his Siſter's Voice, fancy'd himſelf to have been in a Dream, by reaſon he perceiv'd ſome ſmall familiarity betwixt them at other times: But her repeated Importunities and Crying out, ſoon convinc'd him of the Reality of what he before but barely imagin'd. And conſidering withal, what an Odium their Family would undergo, firſt turn'd his Siſter upon the Man, reſolving at once to pin them both to the ground
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:35696:59"/>with his Spit; and was juſt ready to pierce it through their Bodies, had not another of the Family, who perceived now the worſt of the Danger, fortu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nately ſtepp'd in, and ſtopping his Hand, prevented the fatal ſtroke, and interceded for their Pardon. The Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, at firſt, could not eaſily be appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed; but his Paſſion abating, and conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering, the beſt way would be, to keep it as private as they could from the Ears of their Neighbours, he promiſed to unlooſe them; but with this <hi>proviſo,</hi> That they ſhould tye themſelves faſter by a Matrimonial Conjunction, and by that means prevent the Scandal which unavoidably would be brought upon their Family. To this they very joyful conſented; and lovingly Kiſſing as they lay on the ground, ſwore Conſtancy and Fidelity to each other, and in a few days after were marry'd accordingly, and liv'd very happily together for many years, but vow'd never to get both at once into the Smock agen.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="129" type="jest">
               <pb n="100" facs="tcp:35696:60"/>
               <head>129.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman coming along the Road, and ſeeing a blind Man carrying a Cripple on his Back, and being Poe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tically given, thus deſcanted on them:
<q>
                     <l>How happily Fate hath together join'd</l>
                     <l>Two feeble Men! one Lame, the other Blind!</l>
                     <l>The Blind Man hears the Lame, the Lame ſupplies,</l>
                     <l>By his Direction, t'other's want of Eyes.</l>
                     <l>See What the urging power of Need can do!</l>
                     <l>It makes the Blind to ſee, the Lame to go.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="130" type="jest">
               <head>130.</head>
               <p>A company of pretended Cripples, with counterfeit Sores, falſe Legs and Arms, ſitting begging at the bottom of a Hill where a Country Fair was kept; a mad Fellow, to try an Experiment, crying, <hi>Have among you, Blind Harpers!</hi> rowled down a Garden Rowling-ſtone, directly aimed at them. But they fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeeing the danger, cut the Strings that tied up their true Legs, and fell to ſcam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pering, as nimbly as Boys of ſixteen.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="131" type="jest">
               <pb n="101" facs="tcp:35696:60"/>
               <head>131.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman ſeeing a Fellow a Louſing himſelf underneath a Hedge, in a miſerable tatter'd Condition; Friend, <hi>ſays he,</hi> How come you to be in this poor Equipage, ſeeing you have ſuch abundance of live Cattle to diſpoſe of? Alas! Sir, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> that is my misfortune: for although I have a large Stock, I'm forc'd to keep it in my own Hands, for want of a Chapman; and ſhall be conſtrained to do ſo ſtill, unleſs your Worſhip will be pleas'd to take them off, at reaſonable Rates.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="132" type="jest">
               <head>132.</head>
               <p>A merry Poet having marry'd a ſhrew'd Wife, ſoon repented his Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, and complained; and thus fabled:
<q>
                     <l>The Country People once a Wolf did take,</l>
                     <l>Which of their Sheep and Lambs did havock make:</l>
                     <l>To many Deaths to Judge him they began,</l>
                     <l>Till ſtarting up, a newly marry'd Man</l>
                     <pb n="102" facs="tcp:35696:61"/>
                     <l>Lay by: ſaid be, Your Fire, Sword, Guns and Whips,</l>
                     <l>Theſe are light Torture; I have one out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrips</l>
                     <l>All thoſe: If you would puniſh him to'th Life,</l>
                     <l>Fit for his Crimes, Then let him wed a Wife.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="133" type="jest">
               <head>133.</head>
               <p>A Country Gentleman have mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry'd a rich Citizen's Daughter, ſhe car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried down a large Monkey with her: which being chained at the Parlour-door, an Old Woman who was his Tenant, coming to ſpeak with him, took it for his Page, and making a reverend Court'ſie, ſaid, Pray, young Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, Is your Maſter within? At which Pugg grinn'd and chatter'd. Why truly, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> this is very un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>civil, to flout at a Woman that is old enough to be your Mother.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="134" type="jest">
               <head>134.</head>
               <p>A Welſh-man coming to <hi>London,</hi> and ſeeing a Jackanapes ſitting behind the Counter, in a Shop, went in, putting off his Hat, and deſired hur to give
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:35696:61"/>hur a Groat and Eight Tokens for half a Shilling. The Jackanapes took the Money, and whip'd it into the Chink, and then ſat him down again very gravely. The Welſh-man making a clamour for his <hi>ſhange,</hi> the Maſter came out, and ſternly demanded, Whether he came to rob his Shop, or not? No, (reply'd he) but hur come to ſhange Half a Shilling. Where is it? (ſaid the Maſter of the Shop.) Why (reply'd <hi>Shon ap Shinkin</hi>) hur gif it to hur aged Father here, and hur have put it into that Hole. The Shop-keeper laughing at this, gave him Six-pence, without further Enquiry, and ſo diſmiſt him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="135" type="jest">
               <head>135.</head>
               <p>A Fellow for Forgery, being adjudged to loſe his Ears, and the hangman, upon ſearch miſſing them, ſaid, Thou art an errant Cheat; for thou haſt not only deceived others, but even me, who am the very Hand of Juſtice. Why Block<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head, (ſaid he,) Am I bound to find every Raſcal Ears to cut off, <hi>ad infinitum.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="136" type="jest">
               <pb n="104" facs="tcp:35696:62"/>
               <head>136.</head>
               <p>A Man and his Wife falling out, among other Reproachss, ſhe clapping her Hands, cry'd, Ah, you Cuckoldly Rogue! Huſwife (ſaid he) if I am a Cuckold, how the Devil came you to know it?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="137" type="jest">
               <head>137.</head>
               <p>A Man riding along a Road that paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed through a Corn-Field, ſaid to a Swin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd, You have a troubleſome fort of Cattle to deal withal. Yes truly (ſaid the Swinhe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d) they are ſo, and know not a Letter but what I teach them. Why (ſaid the other) do they underſtand Letters? I can't tell that, (again reply'd the Swinherd,) they underſtand my Inſtructions well enough, and one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther too. Why (ſaid the Traveller,) What ſays that Hog that is preſſed by the other? Alas, poor Soul! (reply'd the Swinherd,) he bids him lye further off, and complains that he hurts his Shoulder. Why truly (ſaid the Man) thou art the firſt Hog School-Maſter I
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:35696:62"/>ever met with, in all the Travels of my whole Life.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="138" type="jest">
               <head>138.</head>
               <p>A Man commending his Wife, for the great Love ſhe bore him, another would <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> it. Why (ſaid he) it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> appears in this; As ſoon as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> takes a pleaſure to remove into the very place where I have lain. Ay (ſaid the other) that makes it plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly appear, that ſhe loves your Abſence better than your Company.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="139" type="jest">
               <head>139.</head>
               <p>A conceited Spark, who would be often thruſting himſelf into Ladies Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies, one day bragging of the Favour they allow'd him, and that they were proud to accept of his Favours, fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently begging one thing or other of him. This, Sir, (ſaid an arch Wag that ſat by,) is very true; for I my ſelf have heard them intreat, that you would be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtow your very Abſence on them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="140" type="jest">
               <pb n="106" facs="tcp:35696:63" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>140.</head>
               <p>A Man and his Wife having agreed in bed, in a cold Night, That whoever ſpoke firſt, ſhould ariſe and ſhut the Door, which they had accidentally left open: In the mean while, a rambling Fellow, that was ſhut out of his Lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and a little in drink, came re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ling in; and finding a Bed, crept in, the two Parties lying all the while ſilent: but by and by the Husband perceiving how it was with his Wife, could hold no longer, but ſaid, Why do you ſuffer this? O Husband! (reply'd ſhe,) you have ſpoken firſt, therefore you muſt rife and ſhut the Door.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="141" type="jest">
               <head>141.</head>
               <p>A Youngſter newly come from the Univerſity, who had not ſown his wild Oats, being put into a ſmall Living in the Country; long he had not been there, but a Complaint was made by a preciſe <hi>Non Con,</hi> That he had play'd at Cudgels behind the Church, on a <hi>Sunday,</hi> after Sermon. His Patron check'd him
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:35696:63"/>highly for it, telling him, the Scandal reflected upon himſelf, for placing ſuch a One in the Cure. Why, Sir, (re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd he,) what would you have me do? I am placed over a Company of Block<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>headed People, that forget all that I ſay to them, before they get out of the Church-yard; therefore ſeeing Words are not of force ſufficient to penetrate their thick Skulls, I could conſider of no better way, than to beat my Inſtructions into their Heads, that they might carry them home in their remembrance, and edifie accordingly.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="142" type="jest">
               <head>142.</head>
               <p>An arch Spark being carried before a Juſtice who was none of the wiſeſt, for running his Sword thorough a Tanner's Dog, that breaking out of the yard, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaulted him as he was walking by the Door. Sirrah! (ſaid the Juſtice,) How durſt you kill this honeſt Man's Dog? you, no doubt, have a deſign to rob the Houſe. No indeed, Sir, not I; but I'll ſhow you how it was (ſaid he:) The Dog leaped over the Pails, and came running full at me, as I do at you, with
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:35696:64"/>a Bough, Wough, Wough; and hereupon the Juſtice, being troubled with the Gout, and ſitting in a Chair, he quite over-threw him, Chair and all: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon he cried out, Oh! this murther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Rogue has kill'd me! Make his <hi>Mittimus,</hi> and ſend him to Goal; I'll have him hang'd, whatever comes on't. By this time he was helped up, and a little recovered; Come, Sirrah! (ſays he.) What is your Name? So and ſo (ſaid the Gentleman, telling him what his Name was.) Why (ſaid the Juſtice) that is My Lord ſuch a one's Name. True, Sir, (reply'd the other,) and I am the Man. Oh! are you ſo? then I crave your Mercy, dear Sir, and the caſe is alter'd, (ſaid the Juſtice;) and turning to the Tanner, with a very ſtern Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance, Sirrah! (ſays he,) How durſt you let your Dog looſe, to fly upon ſuch a worthy Gentleman? Come, come, I'll teach you to take more care another time; Make his <hi>Mittimus,</hi> and ſend him to Goal. And accordingly he had been committed, had not the Gentleman in his Generoſity excus'd him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="143" type="jest">
               <pb n="109" facs="tcp:35696:64"/>
               <head>143.</head>
               <p>A Woman at <hi>Wapping</hi> having loſt ſome trivial Matters, was in a great hurry for her Hood and Scarf, to go to a Woman that profeſs'd the Art of <hi>Aſtro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>logy</hi> (you muſt needs know.) Which a Boy about Eight or Nine Years old ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſaid, Where are you running in ſuch haſte? Why (ſaid ſhe) to the Wiſe Woman. Oh, Mother! (reply'd the Boy,) then, good new, let me go with yee; for I never ſaw a VVife VVoman in my life, as yet.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="144" type="jest">
               <head>144.</head>
               <p>A Young Gentlewoman being forced, by the rigour of her Parents, into the Arms of an Old Man, for a great Eſtate, and fruſtrated of marrying One to whom ſhe had given her Promiſe; the two Lovers, however, met privately, and had ſundry Enjoyments; but at laſt, the jealous old Blade, by the Spies he had ſet, intrapp'd them: but they were ſo far from being 'frighted, that they boldly juſtified the Action, ſaying, They
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:35696:65"/>were, in Conſcience, before God, Man and VVife. This vexed the Miſer to the Heart; but not daring to demand Satisfaction with his Sword, he reſolv'd to have it by Law, and accordingly Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſted the Gentleman for a 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> Damages. But upon the Tryal, the Gentleman, who was well belov'd, had ſo many friends in the Jury, that upon the return of the Verdict, they brought in only a Mark Damage for the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff. At which falling into a great rage, VVell (ſays he) Gentlemen, this is monſtrous ſtrange, that having proved my ſelf a Cuckold upon Record, you ſhould give me but a Mark! and ſo flinging out of the Court, ſaid, I pray God that all your VVives may mark you as ſhamefully as mine has done me; and may your Horns be as long as Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber's Poles.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="145" type="jest">
               <head>145.</head>
               <p>A conceited Fop having dreſſed him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf very gay, and being with his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, often peep'd in the Glaſs, and careen'd his VVig; then ſtrutting to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards her, ſaid, Madam, VVho do you
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:35696:65" rendition="simple:additions"/>think is the prettieſt Man you ever ſaw? (imagining ſhe would point out him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf;) but on the contrary, Truly, Sir, (ſaid ſhe,) the Man that is the moſt un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like you, of all Men living.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="146" type="jest">
               <head>146.</head>
               <p>Two Perſons contending about Sing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, a Perſon whom they appointed to decide the Matter pretending to have Skill, but indeed had none, giving his Verdict apprently in the wrong: the injur'd Gentleman ſaid, Now, Sir, I will tell you a Story: Once upon a time, when Birds and Beaſts cou'd ſpeak, a Cuckow and a Nightingale contended who ſung ſweeteſt, or gave the beſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent to their Auditors; but not agreeing, it was put to the next Paſſenger to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cide; which unluckily happen'd to be an Aſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="147" type="jest">
               <head>147.</head>
               <p>Two Sharpers of the Town acciden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tally meeting, fays one, Come, <hi>Jack,</hi> ſince we are ſo happily ſtumbl'd upon one another, let us take a Pint together?
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:35696:66"/>A Match, (ſays the other;) and ſo they went into a Tavern. But drinking about for a while, when they came to examine their Pockets, they found them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves deceived, one thinking the one had, and the other thinking the other had Money enough to defray the Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, when, indeed, both of them could make but Eight Farthings. Hang it then (ſaid the Inviter) we had as good be in for a great deal as a little, ſo they call'd luſtily, till it came to a Crown; then looking out at the Window, as if they had been viewing the deſcent ſays one to the other, I have it now. Upon that, knocking, and deſiring to ſpeak with the Maſter, up he came: Sir, ſays one, we came hither about a Mathematical buſineſs, to meaſure from your Window to the Ground; I have lay'd upon 13 Foot, 9 Inches; my Friend on 13 Foot; and you are to be Judge, that I ſlip not this Line till he goes down to ſee whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther from this Knot (ſhewing it him,) which is juſt ſo much, it reaches the Ground. The Vintner was content. The other Sharper being below in the Street, cry'd, It did not reach by 11 Inches. Pray, Sir, ſays he to the Vint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner.
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:35696:66" rendition="simple:additions"/>hold it here, till I ſtep down and ſee; for I cannot believe him. So down he went, telling the Drawer he had pay'd his Maſter, and away they both ſcowr'd, leaving the String for his Reckoning.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="148" type="jest">
               <head>148.</head>
               <p>A Coffee-man of a very thick Skull, often bragging that a great Eſtate would fall to him before he dy'd; for a Gip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey who had told him his Fortune, had aſſured him of it. A Perſon who had a mind to put upon him, coming in one day, as in puſſing haſte, ſaid, Now, Mr. <hi>N.</hi> I come to tell you brave News: There is an Eſtate left you by One of your old Acquaintance. Who is that? (ſaid he.) Nay, (ſaid the other,) I am out of breath; Let us drink firſt, e're I tell further? With all my heart, Sir, (ſaid the Coffee-man;) What will you pleaſe to drink? Command it, and it ſhall be at your Service? Why (ſaid the Gentlemen) I think, a quart of Mum: And down thunder'd <hi>Ignora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mus</hi> to fetch it; when the Thoughts of this Eſtate employ'd his Faculties to that
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:35696:67"/>degree, that for haſte, he came running up agen with his Spigot in his Hand, whil'ſt the Barrel of Mum run about the Cellar. The Gentleman minding him, could not forbear laughing: Which the other not regarding, inſiſted to know when he ſhould be poſſeſſed of this great Eſtate he talk'd on? Why e'en (ſays the Gentleman) when you come to Years of Diſcretion, and can diſtinguiſh a Lye from an <hi>Aeſop</hi>'s Fable; and ſo leſt him to be banter'd by the reſt of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="149" type="jest">
               <head>149.</head>
               <p>A grave Blade going by a Houſe he had formerly frequented, ſeeing it ſhut-up; and a Bill to Lett it, he demanded what was become of the Owner of it? Why, <hi>reply'd one that ſtood by,</hi> he is gone off, and it is ſeiz'd upon for a Mortgage. Nay, <hi>ſaid old Dry-boots,</hi> I found the Houſe within ſo full of Meat and Drink, when I was there laſt, that I gueſs'd it would grow queaſie-ſtomach'd in a ſhort time, and ſpew out its Maſter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="150" type="jest">
               <pb n="115" facs="tcp:35696:67" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>150.</head>
               <p>An aged Woman being very much indiſpoſed, One came to comfort her, and asked if he ſhould read by her? Yes, if you pleaſe, <hi>ſaid ſhe.</hi> And what ſhall I read? <hi>ſaid be.</hi> Why truly, <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd ſhe,</hi> what you imagine beſt: but now I think further on it, <hi>continu'd ſhe,</hi> I think it had beſt be Matrimony; for that has been very ſweet and comforta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to me formerly; and may yet for ought I know, give ſome Eaſe and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>freſhment by the Power of Imagina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="151" type="jest">
               <head>151.</head>
               <p>A Man with a great red Noſe, being a Paſſenger on Shipboard, was mighty timorous in a Storm: and though the Ship was in danger to be caſt away, the Cabbin-Boy could not forbear laughing, though he receiv'd ſome Baſtinado's for his unſeaſonable mirth. The Storm be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing over, the Party demanded the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of his Laughter? Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> to think how your Noſe would have
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:35696:68" rendition="simple:additions"/>whizz'd, if we had been caſt-away; and made the Water boyl up, as you were going down to the bottom.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="152" type="jest">
               <head>152.</head>
               <p>A Perſon very miſ-ſhapen, would, notwithſtanding, have his Picture drawn: but being covetous withal, when it was finiſh'd, he would not pay the Price agreed on. Well, Sir, <hi>ſaid the Limner,</hi> this is very unfair; however, I value it not a Pin, for I ſhall loſe no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing by it, though you think you have diſappointed me. Why, what will you do with it? <hi>ſaid the Gentleman:</hi> Puh! <hi>continu'd be,</hi> Who d'yee think will give any ſuch Price as I now bid you, for another Man's Picture? Oh! <hi>ſaid the Painter,</hi> it is but altering the Property a little, and that do's it. As how, pray? <hi>ſaid the Gentleman.</hi> Why, <hi>ſaid the Lim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner,</hi> 'tis but putting a Tail to it, and it will paſs for an excellent Babboon, to place in a Nobleman's Houſe of Eaſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. At this the Gentlemen ſtorm'd and bluſter'd at a high rate; but for fear he ſhould do as he ſaid, was forc'd to pay him his Price, and take it himſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="153" type="jest">
               <pb n="117" facs="tcp:35696:68" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>153.</head>
               <p>A Student that was newly marry'd, being a Bed with his Wife, and being uſed, when ſingle, to read himſelf a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſleep, call'd for his Book: But ſhe ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving another kind of Leſſon for him to read, call'd for her Wheel and Spindle. How! <hi>ſaid he;</hi> What mean you by this, now 'tis late? Why truly, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> that I may ſpin, whil'ſt you reel; for none but one reeling drunk, would ſtudy, by Book, for to learn the Bus'neſs we have to do to Night, ſince every one has it by rote.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="154" type="jest">
               <head>154.</head>
               <p>A Sailor that had loſt one of his Arms, marrying a Female that paſs'd for a Virgin; but pretending to be a Critick in Maiden-heads, told her on the Wedding-Night, That ſhe had put a butter'd Bunn upon him. No matter, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> it is good enough for ſuch a one as you, who are but Part of a Man. Why, you Drab, <hi>ſays he,</hi> Do you jear me for being maimed, when it was done,
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:35696:69" rendition="simple:additions"/>valiantly fighting with my Enemy? And why then, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> do you upbraid me with what I have loſt, amorouſly embracing with my Friend? Is it not better to be in Love, than Hatred? You loſt by your Enemy, and I by my Friend; there's the difference, and ſo let us agree it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="155" type="jest">
               <head>155.</head>
               <p>A poor Fellow who had a long time gone under a Scandal among the Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, for his Inſufficiency; ſeveral of them being got into a knot, chatting together, ſeeing him come along, ſome pointed at him with forked Fingers; others clapp'd their Hands, Ha loo, my Dog! When in the <hi>interim,</hi> a grave Matron, ſomething more charitable (you muſt know) thruſting her ſelf into the Gang of Goſſips, without knowing the meaning of this Diverſion, ſaid, Oh! Fye upon you! How can you be ſo hard-hearted, as thus to abuſe a poor Man, that does you no injury. Yes, <hi>ſays one, whiſpering to her,</hi> he has put the Cheat upon our Sex; for he has marry'd a brisk Woman, and has got nothing to
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:35696:69" rendition="simple:additions"/>ſatisfie her. Oh, Rogue! <hi>reply'd ſhe,</hi> has he ſo? Then, Ha loo, my Cat too.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="156" type="jest">
               <head>156.</head>
               <p>A Cooper having a Wife that uſed to take too much of the Juyce of Barley over night, could not keep her Veſſel from leaking a-bed: For which he cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiſing her one morning with a Hoop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtick, divers of her Goſſips came to inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cede for her: ſome chid him, and others intreated, ſaying, ſhe was the weaker Veſſel. Why, Goody Prattle, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> that's the reaſon I am about my work; for when ſhe's well hoop'd, ſhe will be ſtronger, and hold her Water the better.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="157" type="jest">
               <head>157.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman that uſed to Romance egregiouſly, cheapening a large Eel at a Fiſhmongers Stall, and being asked Half a Crown for it; Puh! <hi>ſays he,</hi> I bought one at <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> as thick and as long as the <hi>May-<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>olen</hi> the <hi>Strand,</hi> for that Price, my Man here can juſtifie it. Truly ſaid his Man, (willing to bring his Maſter off, becauſe the Fiſhmonger
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:35696:70" rendition="simple:additions"/>thought it incredible,) I think, Sir, it was ſcarce ſo long, conſidering the Chimney it was roaſted in, but I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve it might be as thick.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="158" type="jest">
               <head>158.</head>
               <p>An Apothecary having over charged his Brain at a Tavern, and no Coach to be got, he was put into a Basket, and the Porter ſent home with him on his Back. Being asked by the Watch, What he had got there? replied, Only A-Pot. I carry.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="159" type="jest">
               <head>159.</head>
               <p>A Taylor being rampant in the ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of his Wife, ſtrowling the Streets for a bit of Harlotry, cruiſing too near danger, fell foul of a Fire-ſhip; which firing his Main-Yard, that communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated the flame to other Parts: ſo that for fear of ſinking into another World, he found himſelf conſtrained to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fitted at a Bottom-Menders (call'd a Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geon,) who in his Bill, reckon'd him ſuch an extravagant rate, <hi>viz.</hi> 70 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> that he would not pay it without Refe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence:
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:35696:70" rendition="simple:additions"/>And Two of the Profeſſion, not to lower the Value of ſo great a Cure, brought it in, That it was a very Reaſonable Bill: So that altho' Mr. Stitch grumbl'd, he was obliged to pay it. But reſolving to be even with him, and not to be out-lengthen'd in his bill, brought him in Eighty Pounds for a Suit and Cloak: Which Two Taylors judged, upon reference, to be very Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable. By which means he out-wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted his Doctor, got his Money, the Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of the Cloaths, and his Cure, for Nothing. This for the Honour of the Tailors, and the Conſcience of either Calling.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="160" type="jest">
               <head>160.</head>
               <p>A handſome young Woman being marry'd to a rich Man who had loſt his Sight by a Blaſt of Powder, ſome blam'd her for it; but an arch Wag, to vindi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate her, wrote thus:
<q>
                     <l>Blame not fair <hi>Celia,</hi> that ſhe marry'd be,</l>
                     <l>Tho' ſhe be fair, to one that could not ſee:</l>
                     <l>For in the thing in which ſhe takes delight,</l>
                     <l>And he do's covet, there's no need of Sight.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="161" type="jest">
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:35696:71"/>
               <head>161.</head>
               <p>A ſcolding Woman being often re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved for the ſharpneſs of her Tongue, ſhe juſtified, That it was the Woman's only Weapon, the Uſe of which they ought not to be denied, (as I find it in a certain Female Author; <hi>viz.</hi>)
<q>
                     <lg>
                        <l>I wonder why Dame Nature thus</l>
                        <l>Her various Giſts diſpences!</l>
                        <l>She every Creature elſe beſide</l>
                        <l>With Arms and Armour fences.</l>
                     </lg>
                     <lg>
                        <l>The <hi>Bull</hi> with bended Horns ſhe arms;</l>
                        <l>With Hoof ſhe guards the <hi>Horſe:</hi>
                        </l>
                        <l>The <hi>Hare</hi> can nimbly run from harms;</l>
                        <l>All know the <hi>Lyon</hi>'s Force.</l>
                     </lg>
                     <lg>
                        <l>The <hi>Bird</hi> can Danger flie on's Wing;</l>
                        <l>The <hi>Fiſh</hi> with Finns adorns:</l>
                        <l>The <hi>Cuckold</hi> too, that harmleſs thing,</l>
                        <l>His Patience guards, and's Horns.</l>
                     </lg>
                     <lg>
                        <l>The <hi>Men</hi> ſhe Valiant makes, and Wiſe,</l>
                        <l>To ſhun and baffle Harms:</l>
                        <l>But to poor <hi>Woman</hi> ſhe denies</l>
                        <l>Armour to give, or Arms.</l>
                     </lg>
                     <pb n="123" facs="tcp:35696:71"/>
                     <lg>
                        <l>Inſtead of all this, ſhe do's do,</l>
                        <l>Sharp Tongues ſhe them beſtows;</l>
                        <l>Which ſerve for Arms and Armour too,</l>
                        <l>'Gainſt all their pow'rful Foes.</l>
                     </lg>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="162" type="jest">
               <head>162.</head>
               <p>A Man having a very turbulent Wife, and ſhe having tired him out with her Curtain-Lectures, he left the Houſe, and plac'd himſelf upon a Chamomile-Bank in the Garden: Which ſhe ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerving, and reſolv'd on a fuller Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venge, threw the Chamber-Pot out of the Window, upon his Head. Well, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> we muſt always expect a Shower after Thunder and Lightning.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="163" type="jest">
               <head>163.</head>
               <p>A Landlord coming one Morning to dunn a Tennant for Rent, found him ſtanding in the Door-way, with his Eye full of Water. How now! <hi>ſaid the Landlord;</hi> What's the matter with you? Why, <hi>reply'd the Tennant,</hi> the Houſe ſmoaks ſo intolerably, there's no endu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring it. I can't, believe that, <hi>ſaid the Landlord;</hi> It never us'd to do ſo. Then,
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:35696:72" rendition="simple:additions"/>pray, <hi>ſaid the Tenant,</hi> to be better ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy'd, go up and ſee. So up he went; and the Room being ſomething dark, the Woman thinking it had been her Husband returned to have t'other Bout at Cudgels for the Breeches, fell to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>labouring him with the Broom-ſtick, crying, You Rogue! I thought I had bang'd you ſufficiently! but now I'll do't to the purpoſe! And ſo drubbing him down Stairs, he caught his Tenant by the Hand, ſaying, Come along! Come along! I find your words true, There is no enduring it: Let us therefore to the next Ale-houſe, and conſult how it may be remedy'd.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="164" type="jest">
               <head>164.</head>
               <p>A Young Woman being marry'd to a Man of Years, and having a brisk Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice, he perceiv'd by the Language of her Eyes, and ſome other Love-Motions, that ſhe bid him come on if he dare: Therefore, his Maſter being out of Town, he reſolving to run the hazard, got into her Bed, and lay as ſnug as a Thief in a Mill, expecting her coming: and accordingly ſhe came, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſs'd,
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:35696:72"/>and went in, not knowing of his being there; for he had hid himſelf over Head and Ears. But no ſooner ſhe perceived an unexpected Bed-fellow, but ſhe ſtarted, and was about to cry-out. At which, he ſaid, Pray, Miſtreſs, don't be frighted; 'tis only I. You! Sirrah! you impudent Rogue! <hi>reply'd ſhe;</hi> How came you here? Indeed. <hi>ſaid he,</hi> now I conſider better, coming up in the dark, I have miſtook my Chamber; and heartily begging your Pardon, I'll retire. No, <hi>ſaid ſhe;</hi> now you are here, I command you to ſtay till Morning, that I may make you ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible of your VVeakneſs; but be ſure you preſume not the like again, for fear I ſhould acquaint your Maſter with it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="165" type="jest">
               <head>165.</head>
               <p>A downright Country Fellow, Son to a Farmer, having caſt his Eyes upon another Farmer's Daughter, deſired his Father to ſpeak to her Father, that he might have her to Wife: (For it is the laudable Cuſtome, in ſome Countries, for the Fathers to make up the Match between their Children, over a Pot of
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:35696:73"/>Ale, Unſight, Unſeen, as the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try Phraſe is.) The Old Men agreed; and then came <hi>Dick</hi> to court his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, and addreſs'd himſelf to her in this Complemental manner. Well, <hi>Joan,</hi> Do'ſt thou know what my Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſaid to thy Vather? No indeed, <hi>Richard,</hi> not I, <hi>reply'd ſhe.</hi> Law yee now! <hi>ſaid he;</hi> What a Vool was thy Vather, he did not tell thee? Why they have agreed, That you and I ſhall be buckled toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, as Man and Wife. Alas! <hi>Richard, reply'd ſhe,</hi> I believe you are but in Jeſt? Indeed and good troth, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I am in Earneſt. I can't think it, <hi>ſaid ſhe;</hi> for I know you may have my Betters. That I know well enough, <hi>reply'd down-right</hi> Dick; but you ſhall ſerve turn, if you will: and without any more a-doe, I'll take thee, for better for worſe, as thy Vather took thy Mother.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="166" type="jest">
               <head>166.</head>
               <p>A Man of a very ſqueamiſh Stomach, coming into a Cook's Shop, in <hi>Smith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field,</hi> to purchaſe a Dinner; but it being <hi>Bartholomew-Fair-time,</hi> and the People ſweating at the Fire, and otherwiſe em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd,
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:35696:73"/>though he ſpoke ſeveral times, they minded him not: ſo that being overcome with the Steam of the Meat, and great Heat of the Fire, his Appe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tite went from him, and he was going out. The ſurly Cook, though before not at leiſure, now clapt hold on his Shoulder, and charged him with Running away, and not Paying his Reckoning. The Man told him he had had nothing, but had filled his Belly with the Scent. Why, that's all one, <hi>ſaid the Cook;</hi> a Belly-full's a Belly-full, though it be of Air; and you ſhall pay me for <hi>that,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you go, ſeeing you have troubled my Shop. The Cook inſiſting on this, it was agreed to be put to reference: And in the mean time, a Natural Fool coming by, it was agreed, on both Sides, that he ſhould decide it. Let me ſee, Mr. Cook, <hi>ſaid the Fool,</hi> a couple of empty Diſhes? Which were brought. Now, <hi>ſaid the Fool to the other,</hi> Let me ſee a Piece of Mony? Which he pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced. Then he put the Mony be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Diſhes, and gingling it about, cry'd, Do you hear it, Mr. Cook? Yes, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> but I had rather have it in my Pocket. No, <hi>reply'd the Fool;</hi> my
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:35696:74"/>Award is, That you ſhall be ſatisſy'd with the Gingling of the Money, as the Man was with the Scent of the Meat.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="167" type="jest">
               <head>167.</head>
               <p>A Perſon of Quality, deſirous to beg a Gentleman for a Fool, thereby to get his Eſtate, made great Intereſt at Court in that Affair. But the Gentleman be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to have a Hearing, before it could be allowed, ſaid, I wonder this Noble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man ſhould be deſirous to rob me and my Poſterity, under pretence, That I am a Fool! Why, grant I am an Ideot; my Father that begot me was a Wiſe Man: And why then may not I, who am a Fool, beget wiſe Children? while this Nobleman, for ought I know, as Wiſe as he is, may have a Fool to his Son, as well as my Father. This reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Anſwer daſh'd the Project; and the Nobleman had only a ſlap with a Fox's Tail, for his pains.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="168" type="jest">
               <pb n="129" facs="tcp:35696:74"/>
               <head>168.</head>
               <p>A Fool coming to a Gentleman's Houſe, and in the Tapeſtry-Hangings ſeeing the Picture of a Fool wrought in, he very fairly takes his Knife and cuts it out, and privately hid it. Soon after, running to the Maſter of the Houſe, he ſaid. Come, <hi>Harry,</hi> give me a Bottle of Sack, for ſaving your Hangings. How ſo! <hi>Jack! ſaid the Gentleman;</hi> How have you ſav'd'em? Were they on fire? No, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> but by cutting out the Picture of the Fool that was in them: for had my Maſter ſeen it, he would have begg'd them, as he did me and my Eſtate.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="169" type="jest">
               <head>169.</head>
               <p>A Perſon who was a great Eater and Drinker, delighting in Gluttony and Riot, courting, one day, a brisk young Widow, among other complemental Expreſſions, ſaid, Madam, I love you as well as I do my own Soul: By all that's Good! — Nay, Nay, <hi>ſaid ſhe, inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupting him,</hi> you need not ſwear it; for
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:35696:75" rendition="simple:additions"/>by the courſe of Life you lead, it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears, you have no regard for its wel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fare: but if you had ſaid, You lov'd me as well as you do your Body, there might have been ſomething in that; ſeeing you are at ſo great Care and Charge, in cramming it every day.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="170" type="jest">
               <head>170.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow ſeeing the rude Rabble a pulling down a Bawdy-houſe, ſaid, Ah! What a ſhame is this, to be ſuffered! For it they be thus permitted to go on, where, in a ſhort time, ſhall we find a Houſe ſtanding in <hi>England?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="171" type="jest">
               <head>171.</head>
               <p>A Quaker having ſold a Man a Horſe, whoſe Eyes, though they appeared tol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lerably fair, were, nevertheleſs, ſtone-blind: ſo the Jockey asked him, after he had pay'd down the Mony, what Faults he had. Do'ſt thou ſee any in him! <hi>ſays yea and Nay.</hi> No, truly, <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd the Jockey,</hi> not I. Then I'll affure you, <hi>ſaid the Man of Conſcience,</hi> upon the VVord of a Friend, he ſees none in
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:35696:75" rendition="simple:additions"/>thee. And ſo, with a Quibble, the Biter was bit.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="172" type="jest">
               <head>172.</head>
               <p>A down-right Country Fellow being troubled with a Standing-Ague, which put him to pain, he went to a Quack-Doctor, and made known his Grievance to him: VVho with a Cloth, and cold VVater, reduced the rebellious Member to a quiet temper; for which he gave him Half a Crown. But a while after, being in the ſame Predicament, and go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for another Application, when in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of the Doctor, he found only his VVife at home; who being inform'd of his Grievance, took another way to cure him, with a more proper Remedy; the newneſs and ſtrangeneſs of which ſo tickled his Conceit, that he offered her a Crown; but ſhe having received her Satisfaction before, would take no Mony: ſo after many Scrapes and Cringes, he departed. But ſearce was he got a Bow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhoot from the Houſe. e're the Doctor, coming homeward, eſpy'd him, telling the Gentlemen in his Company what he was, and upon what account he had
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:35696:76" rendition="simple:additions"/>been at his Houſe; and, to pleaſe them, reſolv'd to put a Joak upon Hob-nail: And well! <hi>ſays he,</hi> honeſt Fellow! How ſtands it now with you? I ſee you have been at my Houſe again. In good vaith! Zur, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> it Stands not at all with me now; for your VVife put it into a warm place, and lay'd it preſently, and for never a Varthing. At this the Doctor bluſh'd; and the Gentlemen laugh'd till their Sides ak'd, to find the Doctor ſo finely dubb'd of the Forked-Order.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="173" type="jest">
               <head>173.</head>
               <p>A Butcher being made Mayor of a ſmall Corporation, his VVife fancy'd, that by reaſon of this new Honour, ſhe ſhould be highly reverenc'd by her Neighbours. So coming to Church the next <hi>Sunday</hi> juſt as the <hi>Creed</hi> began, the People all ſtarted up, it being uſual to ſtand when it is reading; Miſtreſs <hi>Mayoreſs</hi> imagining it was done in reſpect to her, cry'd out, VVell, good People, I ſee now, you have ſome good Breeding, and know how to behave your ſelves be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore your Betters; for which you may
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:35696:76"/>expect my Husband's Kindneſs, before he goes out of his Place.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="174" type="jest">
               <head>174.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow, that had never heard Cathedral Muſick, coming into the Choir, and there liſming a while to the Organs and the melodious Harmony of the Singing Men, cry'd out, as if he had been tranſported, Lord! muſt I go to Heaven preſently? Let me but go home firſt, and take leave of my Wife and Children, and then I'll go moſt willingly.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="175" type="jest">
               <head>175.</head>
               <p>A covetous fellow having an indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent Fortune, would often brag, how bravely he would live, if he could en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe it to ſo much more: which, in proceſs of time, happen'd according to his deſire, with an Overpluſs; and then he lived more niggardly than before, hardly allowing himſelf Neceſſaries for the Support of Life or Decency: When one day, paſſing by One's Door with whom he was at enmity, the Man ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:35696:77"/>there, ſaid, Well, Neighbour, you grow Richer and Richer; and I pray God to ſend you as much morre as you have. Why that Wiſh from you, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> when I know you hate me? That makes me wiſh ſo, <hi>ſays the other,</hi> that you may double your Covetouſneſs, and ſtarve your ſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="176" type="jest">
               <head>176.</head>
               <p>A raw Country Wench being newly come to an Inn to live, a Gentleman ordered her to greaſe his Boots againſt Morning; which ſhe accordingly did, and ſet them in a Loft where Rats were uſed to haunt, and ſeveral Holes were ſoon eat in them: which ſhe finding, early in the Morning ran into the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman's Chamber, in a great fright, crying out, Oh, Sir! the ſaddeſt and ſtrangeſt News you ever heard in your whole Life! What is that? <hi>ſaid he,</hi> (thinking no leſs than that half the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try had been ſunk by an Earthquake.) Why, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> the Rats have eat your Boots, Man! And is that ſo ſtrange! <hi>replied he;</hi> ſuch Chances have often hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen'd: but if thou had'ſt brought me
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:35696:77" rendition="simple:additions"/>certain News, That my Boots had eaten up the Rats; <hi>that</hi> had been worth the hearing.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="177" type="jest">
               <head>177.</head>
               <p>A rich Miſer having made a poor Man wait on him for ſome Mony he promiſed him; at laſt began to banter him, ſaying, If he could perſuade him to it, he ſhould have it. Well, <hi>ſaid the other,</hi> there is but one thing now, that I would perſuade you to, and that I would do, if it was poſſible. And what is that? ſaid he? Prithee, let me know it? Why truly, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> to perſuade you to hang your ſelf, that the World might have one Knave the leſs in it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="178" type="jest">
               <head>178.</head>
               <p>A brisk Laſs, asking a Gallant, How it came to be a Cuſtom, That the Men always make the firſt Addreſs to the VVomen? That does not always hold good, <hi>replied he:</hi> but however, the rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon is, Becauſe the Men always come when they are prepared; but the VVo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men need no time for that, for they are ready at all times.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="179" type="jest">
               <pb n="136" facs="tcp:35696:78"/>
               <head>179.</head>
               <p>A Fellow being to be Hang'd with others, for Robbing a Houſe, his VVife came after him to the Gallows. At which he grew very angry, ſaying, Get you home Huſwife, and waſh your Diſhes; there cannot be a Meeting in all the Country, but you muſt make one among them, with a Murrain t'yee!</p>
            </div>
            <div n="180" type="jest">
               <head>180.</head>
               <p>VVhen Popery, of late, began to be rampant in <hi>England,</hi> ſome Prieſts being jolly at a Tavern near <hi>Somerſet-Houſe,</hi> were diſputing which was the Higheſt Saint. One ſaid, St. <hi>Dominick;</hi> ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, St. <hi>Ignatius:</hi> And ſo not agreeing, they reſolved to put it to the Drawer, when he came up with the next Bottle. VVhich being done; Puh! <hi>ſaid he;</hi> Can't you tell that? Every Fool that looks upon a Sign, can tell that. VVell! And which of them, ſay you, is the Higheſt? becauſe you pretend to ſuch Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge? <hi>ſays he who had ſtood up for</hi> Igna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tius. Why, truly, <hi>reply'd the Drawer,</hi>
                  <pb n="137" facs="tcp:35696:78" rendition="simple:additions"/>St. <hi>George:</hi> for he rides a Horſe bac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>, and all the reſt go on Foot.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="181" type="jest">
               <head>181.</head>
               <p>A Man chiding his Younger Son, for being a Sluggard; ſaid, His Elder Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther had the good luck to be abroad early, before the Roads were much fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented, and had found a Bag of Mony. Ay, Father, <hi>ſaid he;</hi> but the Owner, who got up ſo early, and loſt it, had better have been a bed, as I am.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="182" type="jest">
               <head>182.</head>
               <p>Two Country Fellows going along the Streets, gaping all the way at the Signs, at laſt they came to that of the <hi>Mermaid;</hi> which put them to a ſtand, what to make of it. Oh! <hi>ſays he,</hi> now I know what it is; It is a Lady with a Fiſh in her Arſe. Ay! but how got it in? <hi>ſays the other.</hi> It may be, <hi>reply'd his Companion,</hi> it might be, when ſhe waſh'd her ſelf laſt in the Sea. This being learnedly diſcussed, one of them ſtep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping forward, and ſeeing the Sign of the <hi>Unicorn,</hi> cryed, Lau yee! Here is
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:35696:79"/>a ſtranger thing! What is this call'd? Why, you Fool! <hi>ſaid the other:</hi> Don't you know what that is? Why, 'tis a Horſe with a Barber's Pole in his Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="183" type="jest">
               <head>183.</head>
               <p>An ignorant Blockhead, complaining for a great deal of Mony that was Owing him; was asked, who was his Debtor? reply'd, By one that had been dead ſeven years: yet he was reſolved to ſue him for it, for all that; for he ſhould not think to cheat him ſo. At this the hearers began to laugh, telling him, the Dead are not ſenſible, nor ever pay Debts; therefore it was but a folly to expect it. Hey day! <hi>ſays he,</hi> that's very pretty, indeed! Why, by this means, when a Man has a mind to cheat all the World, it is but to die, and they may go look their Remedy.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="184" type="jest">
               <head>184.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman who took a great de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light in Cock-fighting, ſent his Bag of Cocks, by an Iriſh Servant, to the Pit,
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:35696:79"/>where a great Match was to be fought <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat day, charging him to keep them <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>oſe till he came. But <hi>O Donnel</hi> being <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>arly there, forgetting his Orders, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to have a little Sport, to paſs away <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e time, and ſo threw the three Cocks <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nto the Pit; who being of the right <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>rain, fell immediately together by the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ars, ſometimes one to one, ſometimes two upon one, and ſometimes all in a huddle: whil'ſt <hi>O Donnel</hi> leapt and skipt about them, and challenging any one to wage Two new Halfpenny Half-Croon Pieſhes which beat. But ſo mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal was the Combat, that two were kill'd out-right, and the other mortally wounded. His Maſter hereupon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and ſeeing what had happen'd, in a great Rage, ſaid, You confounded Dog! How came this about? <hi>By my Shalwaſhion, Dear Joy, if dee wot no mauk muſh anger, Y will tell dee, indeed: Y did pot dem down upon de plauſh here, and dey did faul out, as if dey had never ſeen one anoder before: De'ell tauk'em, if Y did ſhee de like in all my life now, dat dey ſhou'd mauk ſuch falling-out, and pot the kill upon one anoder, and yet be Broders, born and bred in one and de ſame Houſh, is very
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:35696:80"/>ſtrange, in good fait, metinks, truly, my Dear Joy!</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="185" type="jest">
               <head>185.</head>
               <p>An Iriſh Footman coming to a No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleman's Houſe, deſired of the Porter, that he might ſpeak with his Lord, for he had earneſt Bus'neſs with him. He told him he was at Dinner, and he muſt wait till his Lord had Din'd. But he told him again, That his Buſineſs was ſo Earneſt, that he could not ſtay two Moments. The Porter not knowing of what Concern it might be, whiſper'd his Lord in the Ear; Who left the Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, and came out to him. Says <hi>Teague</hi> to him, <hi>Are you his Lord's Grauſh?</hi> Yes (ſayd he;) What is your Buſineſs? <hi>Only, Y wou'd pray dee to do me de favour, to do me de kindneſh, to tell thy Man,</hi> Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trick, <hi>when he comes home, Y wou'd fain ſpeak with him, about earneſt buſineſs.</hi> And is this all (reply'd the Nobleman) that you have troubled me for? <hi>Yes, indeed, Joy,</hi> (ſaid the other. Then (ſaid the Nobleman) it will be requiſite that I give you ſomething in remembrance of it, and ſo order'd him to the Whip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping-Poſt,
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:35696:80"/>where he received a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward at the Hand of the Common Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, ſuitable to the Affront put upon ſo Noble a Gentleman.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="186" type="jest">
               <head>186.</head>
               <p>A French-man's Mony falling ſhort, he was forced to buy a Fore Quarter of Mutton with a pair of Horns on it, for his <hi>Sunday</hi>'s Dinner: but it being an un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uſual Diſh, he was non-pluſs'd how to dreſs it; deſiring the Butcher to give him a Receipt, how to order it. The which whil'ſt he was doing, a Dog ſnatch'd it off the Block where he had <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>aid it; and was got a pretty way, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the People cry'd out, French<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man! French-man! You have loſt your Sheep's-Head. At which, turning about, and not finding himſelf capable of overtaking the Thief, ſays, Let him go, Let him go, like a Fool as he is; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or he'll be never the better for it, ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing I have the Receipt, and he knows not how to dreſs it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="187" type="jest">
               <pb n="142" facs="tcp:35696:81" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>187.</head>
               <p>Another of this Country, waſhing a parcel of raw Tripe at a Brook, which he intended to boyl for his Dinner; and having done, and laid it behind him<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> whil'ſt he was waſhing his Hands, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Dog came ſlily and ſtole it away. The<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Monſieur</hi> being angry thus to be diſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed of his Dinner, a while after ſeeing the Dog, reſolved to catch him<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> and chaſtize him; but the Curr ſhunn'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> him: Whereupon, to allure him into his Clutches, he pull'd out his Bauble and ſhaking it, cry'd, <hi>Here Dog, M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Tripe; Mo Tripe, Dog.</hi> But the Cur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> was too Old, to be caught with Chaff.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="188" type="jest">
               <head>188.</head>
               <p>A Fellow whoſe Name was <hi>Roac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> reeling along by a River-ſide, and being lop-heavy, plung'd in, and lamentable cry'd out for help. But his Companic<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> being as drunk as he, minded him no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> till he had ſcrabbled out of his own a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> cord; then asked him how he fared<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Oh! (ſaid he that had been double
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:35696:81" rendition="simple:additions"/>dipp'd,) You are a truſty Stick, indeed; I might have been drowned, for what care you took of me. Truly, (ſays the other,) I thought there was no Danger, ſeeing you was but in your own Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="189" type="jest">
               <head>189.</head>
               <p>A drunken Fellow, reeling home in a froſty Night, when the Moon ſhone, finding himſelf very ſleepy, laid him down on a Bank that diſcended ſloap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into a ſhallow Ditch of Water; and with tumbling and toſſing, ſlid with his Feet into it, and ſo lay ſnoring till Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple came by, and found him in that poſture: they jogg'd him hard, for a time, e're they could wake him at all; and then, between half-'wake and 'wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king, he cry'd, Friends, Pray don't di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſturb my reſt at this time a night, but go to your own Beds, for I can ſpare you no room; only lay a few more Cloaths upon the Feet, and don't put out the Candle.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="190" type="jest">
               <pb n="144" facs="tcp:35696:82"/>
               <head>190.</head>
               <p>A drunken Fellow being brought be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore a Country Juſtice, and upon the Interrogatories put to him, nothing could be got out of him, but that, <hi>Your Worſhip's wondrous Wiſe.</hi> So he was com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the <hi>Roundhouſe</hi> that Night, and ordered to be brought in the Morning, when he ſhould be ſober. Then ſaid the Juſtice, How now! Sirrah! How came you to ſo Drunk, laſt Night? Lay down your Ten Groats. Was I Drunk, (reply'd he;) indeed I know nothing of it. It may be ſo, (ſaid the Juſtice;) you have ſlept ſince; but then nothing could be got out of you, but, <hi>Your Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips wondrous Wiſe.</hi> Did I ſay ſo? (ſaid the Fellow.) Yes, (ſaid the Juſtice; here are ſeveral to witneſs it. It needs not, (reply'd the Fellow;) I'll take your Worſhip's Word: and if I did ſay ſo, I'm ſure I was Drunk; and it is but reaſon, that I ſhould pay, for putting ſuch an Affront upon you, that you little de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve from any body's mouth; thorefore give me Two-pence, and here is Three and Six-pence.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div n="2" type="part">
            <pb n="145" facs="tcp:35696:82" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE SECOND PART: Containing <hi>Bulls, Blunders, Banters, Quib<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, Repartees, Wheedles,</hi> and <hi>Pleaſant Stories.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">With A Particular <hi>Character</hi> of a <hi>Wheedle,</hi> and the <hi>Art</hi> of <hi>Wheedling.</hi>
            </head>
            <div n="1" type="jest">
               <head>1</head>
               <p>THree Men walking in the Fields, about the beginning of Harveſt-time, cryes one on a ſudden, Look yonder, <hi>Tom!</hi> there's a bunch of Red Black-berries already! At which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e laugh'd, crying, It was a Bull. Why <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o! (ſays the third,) Are not Black-berries Red when they are Green?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="jest">
               <pb n="146" facs="tcp:35696:83" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>2.</head>
               <p>A Country Gentleman having a grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Eſtate, than Stock of Underſtanding, being upon hard Travel, the Horſes tier'd, ſo that he was forced to put into an Inn: but not liking his Accommoda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and being withal in haſte to ſee a Miſtreſs he was going to be married to, the Bargain being already made by Proxy, he fell a ſwearing at his Coach-man, for not driving on. Sir, <hi>ſaid the Coach-man,</hi> the Horſes are able to go no further. Why, hang 'em then, for founder'd Jades, leave 'em in the Inn, and drive on the Coach without 'em.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="jest">
               <head>3.</head>
               <p>Two Iriſh-men ſeeing a Great Officer in a Mazarine Blue Coat, Embroider'd with Silver; ſays one to the other, <hi>Dat<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> is very pretty Garſhment; Y wou'd pot great<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> kindneſh upon any one dat wou'd be ſo ſhive<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> as to put ſuch a one upon my Bauk, juſt now<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Ah!</hi> (ſaid the other,) <hi>Dear Joy, if <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> cou'd get a Scarlet S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>oat of dat colour, how very fine ſhou'd Y then be, indeed now!</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="jest">
               <pb n="147" facs="tcp:35696:83" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>4.</head>
               <p>A Fellow having footed it much, till the Soles of his Shoes were about to leave the Upper-Leather, went to a Tranſla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor, and making ſome wry Faces, told him, He would give him three-half-pence, which was all the Mony he had in the World. Give it me! (ſays S. <hi>Hugh;</hi>) I prithee, for what? Why, (reply'd the other,) only to do me the kindneſs to put two Heel-pieces on the Toes of my Shoes, to keep the Water out.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="jest">
               <head>5.</head>
               <p>A ſimple Fellow that had ſtole a Horſe, being before a Judge, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving ſome odd Notions, buzz'd into his Head, he pray'd him to direct the Jury to find him guilty of Manſlaughter, and not of Felony; for he had rather be Burnt in the Hand, than Hang'd.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="jest">
               <head>6.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow who had been at <hi>London,</hi> and among ſome ſmall matter
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:35696:84"/>of Mony receiving a Guinea, and never having had one before, ſhew'd it to his Country-folks, as a Rarity: Who ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with their Mouths at half-cock, much admir'd its luſtre, asking if there were any ſtore of them at <hi>London?</hi> Yes, in good troth, are they, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> for a Man can't take Forty Shillings, but he is compell'd to take Seven or Eight of 'em, though he had rather have Silver.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="jest">
               <head>7.</head>
               <p>A Perſon having been at a Noble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man's Houſe, where there was a great Feaſt; a Neighbour, at his return, asked him what Chear he had there? Oh! very great ſtore, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> for there was four or five Second Courſes brought up and plac'd on the Table.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="jest">
               <head>8.</head>
               <p>One coming in great haſte, to give notice of the Death of a Man that dy'd ſuddenly; and being asked, when he died? Why truly, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> even to Morrow Morning. Ay! <hi>ſaid he;</hi> that's ſtrange! And when, pray, is he to be
<pb n="149" facs="tcp:35696:84" rendition="simple:additions"/>buried? Why, Yeſterday, <hi>reply'd he.</hi> Why, this is a ſtrange Contradiction, and cannot be probable. In good ſober ſadneſs, ſays the Fellow, they told me ſo; I know no otherwiſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="jest">
               <head>9.</head>
               <p>A Fellow that newly came up to <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> as an Apprentice, being ſent for a Pound of Candles, and in his return, giving too large a ſtep over the Kennel, ſtumbl'd, and all di<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ted them: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, having a croſs Miſtreſs, he went to a neighbouring Ale-houſe, and in a Pail of Water waſhed them. But then being wet, an arch Wagg advis'd him to hang them by the Fire to dry, whil'ſt he tippl'd his Pint. But prating, and not minding them, the Fire being very hot, had quickly melted all the Tallow; when turning about and miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing them, Well, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I have often heard that this <hi>London</hi> is a very thieving place, and now I find it true; for ſome body has put his Arm down the Chim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, ſtole my Candles out of the top of it, and left only a bunch of Candle-Wicks in the room of them; and, with
<pb n="150" facs="tcp:35696:85" rendition="simple:additions"/>this lamentable Story he went home to accept of a broken Pate.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="jest">
               <head>10.</head>
               <p>An old Inn-keeper having married a brisk young Woman in the Town, a Spark that came to the Inn, had a great mind to be tickling her Fancy; and by Ogling, ſqueezing her Finger, and ſoftly treading on her Toe, made her under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand the Paſſion he had for her; ſo that they ſoon came to a Parley, and he found little difficulty to make her pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe him to Surrender; but a conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient Place was next to be aſſigned, for the Signing and Exchanging Articles. At length they appointed to meet, when it was dark, in the Houſe of Eaſement. But when they were in the mid'ſt of their merry Conceit, the Old Man came thundering at the Door. Who's there? <hi>ſays the Spark?</hi> It is I, <hi>reply'd he;</hi> Let me in; I'm in haſte. You can't come in <hi>ſays the Spark;</hi> I am in before you, and you muſt ſtay while I have done. Why ſo? <hi>ſays the Husband;</hi> there are two Holos. I know that, <hi>ſays the Spark;</hi> but I am juſt got into one, and
<pb n="151" facs="tcp:35696:85"/>the other is all befoul'd: With which flamm he ſent him away, to eaſe him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf upon the Dunghill, while the two Lovers went on with their Show.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="jest">
               <head>11.</head>
               <p>Many People have wonder'd at the meaning of Throwing at Cocks on a <hi>Shrove-Tueſday;</hi> which, for your better Information, take as followeth. A good Woman, you muſt know, once upon a time, in her Husband's abſence, had occaſion for ſome ſecret Service to be done her by a Neighbour of hers; to which only the Cocks and Hens were privy: When Crowing-time came, the old Cock ſtanding a tiptoe on his Dung<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hill, began his uſual Crow; which the Woman's guilty Conſcience interpreted thus, <hi>My Maſter's a Cuckold, I <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>now it.</hi> Do you ſo? <hi>ſays ſhe;</hi> I'll ſpoil your tel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of Tales: Whereupon, catching him up, ſhe was about to wring off his Neck; but thinking that too eaſie a Pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment for ſo great a Crime, ſhe gave him to a parcel of rude Boys, to knock on the head with a Cat-ſtick: And ſo be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan the fooliſh Cuſtome.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="jest">
               <pb n="152" facs="tcp:35696:86"/>
               <head>12.</head>
               <p>A Country Farmer, who drudg'd on only for the Payment of Rent, and a little Victuals; yet to add to his Miſery, was troubled with a turbulent, ſcolding Wife; as one day he was at Plough, weary and ſweating, his Horſes were Jaded; and croſſing him, he fretted ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tremely; and in his Paſſion, call'd out for the Devil to come immediately and fetch them away: When (as the Story goes) up came one of <hi>Belzebub</hi>'s menial Servants, to fulfil his Requeſt. At whoſe terrible Shape, and fierce Countenance, the poor Man being affrighted, intreated his abſence; for he had no buſineſs with with him. Why, ſaid <hi>Mephoſtophiles,</hi> did you not call me to take your Horſes? Ay, <hi>ſaid he;</hi> but I was only in jeſt. Oh! <hi>reply'd the Devil,</hi> I don't uſe to be jeſted with, but will have ſomething e're I go. Then, <hi>ſaid the poor Man,</hi> pray go and take my Wife away. Then skipp'd the Infernal Meſſenger, and horſing her on his back, flew with her to his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter's Dungeon: but there ſhe kept ſuch a Clamour, made ſuch Cabals and Diſtur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bances,
<pb n="153" facs="tcp:35696:86"/>that the poor Dog of a Devil was ordered, upon pain of being hung up by the heels in a ſmoaky Chimney for a Thouſand Years, to carry her back again. But then the Husband would not take her, declaring ſhe was bad be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, but now ſhe would be ten times worſe. Why? ſaid <hi>Mephoſtophiles;</hi> If you will do it, I will make you a fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Doctor; and preſcribe what you will, it ſhall have ſucceſs, if you ſee me at the Bed's-Head; but if at the Feet, the Party will die. This being agreed, the firſt he practis'd on, was an Uſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer, whoſe Conſcience ſtarted at the Thoughts of Another World: but the Devil, it ſeems, appearing at the Feet, he very ſadly told him, He muſt die. Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> talk not to me of Death; uſe your beſt Endeavours to ſave me, and I'll give you a Hundred Pound. Upon this, he beckoned the Devil to come up to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ed's Head: but he ſhook his Horns, as unwilling to do it. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon, ſtepping to him, and whiſpering in his Ear, he ſaid Before <hi>George,</hi> if yee don't do it, I'll fetch my Wife to you. The terrour of which Threat made him skip thither preſently, and then he gave
<pb n="154" facs="tcp:35696:87"/>his Patient comfort under his Affliction in a very ſhort time.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="jest">
               <head>13.</head>
               <p>A <hi>Quaker</hi> that was a Barber, being ſued by a Parſon for Tythes; <hi>Yea and Nay</hi> went to him, and demanded the reaſon, why he troubled him, ſeeing he never had any Dealings with him in his whole Life. Why, <hi>ſays the Parſon,</hi> it is for Tythes. For Tythes! <hi>ſays the Quaker;</hi> I prithee, Friend, upon what Account? Why, <hi>ſaid the Parſon,</hi> for Preaching in the Church. Alas! then, <hi>reply'd the Quaker,</hi> I have nothing to do to pay thee; for I come not there, Oh! but you might, <hi>ſays the Parſon;</hi> for the Doors are always open, at convenient Times: And thereupon, told him, he would be pay'd, ſeeing it was his due. <hi>Yea and Nay</hi> hereupon, ſhaked his Ears, and making ſeveral wry Faces, depar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, and immediately entred his Action, it being in a Corporation Town, againſt the Parſon, for Forty Shillings. The Parſon, upon notice of this, came to him, and very hotly demanded, why he put ſuch a Diſgrace upon him? and for
<pb n="155" facs="tcp:35696:87" rendition="simple:additions"/>what he did owe him the Mony? Truly, Friend, <hi>reply'd the Quaker,</hi> for Trimming. For Trimming! <hi>ſaid the Parſon;</hi> why, I was never Trimm'd by you in my Life. Oh! but thou might'ſt have come and been Trimm'd, if thou hadſt pleas'd, for my Doors are always open, at con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient Times, as well as thine.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="14" type="jest">
               <head>14.</head>
               <p>In former days, an ambitious Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlewoman, deſirous to be a Lady, had indented with her Husband on Articles of Marriage, That he ſhould be Knigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted. Which coming in, in diſcourſe with another Gentlewoman, ſhe ask'd how much that Honour would coſt? Why, <hi>reply'd the other,</hi> about an Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds. Why then, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> mine ſhall never be at that Charge; for I'll Dubb him my ſelf firſt, and ſo may you yours, and ſave the Mony, if you be wiſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="15" type="jest">
               <head>15.</head>
               <p>A young Scholar, the Son of a Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, coming to viſit hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Parents, put out
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:35696:88"/>many Quibbles: which made the Country Fellows that came to ſee him, ſtare, and imagine he Conjur'd, and was calling up <hi>Mephoſtophiles</hi> to ſhow Tricks. But one night, being at Supper, and a couple of Fowls ſet on the Table, to ſhow his further Skill, he muſt needs be chop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping Logick: Now, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> Father, I'll ſhow what Learning can do: You ſee theſe Two Fowls. Ay, (ſaid the Father, and ſo ſaid the Mother.) Well then, <hi>continu'd he,</hi> I'll ſhow you how to make Three of them. That's brave! (ſays the Old Woman,) and will quickly encreaſe our Store: But how (continu'd ſhe) do you make that appear? Oh! (ſaid he,) by Logick: As thus; Here's One, is there not? Yes, (ſaid ſhe.) Then ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king up the other, Here's Two, (ſaid he: Now, Two and One makes Three. Well (ſaid the Father,) I think you have made it out pretty well; we will have theſe Two, and you ſhall have the Third for your ſelf: And ſo our Logician, for his Quibble's ſake, was forc'd to go ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perleſs to bed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="16" type="jest">
               <pb n="157" facs="tcp:35696:88"/>
               <head>16.</head>
               <p>An Old Woman having forgotten her Spectacles, and ſeeing ſome People crowding about a great Babboon, dreſs'd up in Antick Faſhion, took it for the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian Embaſſador, ſqueez'd in among them; and ſeeing ſome laugh, ſaid, O fye! good People; Are you not aſham'd to uſe Strangers at this rate? I proteſt, it is no wonder that you are us'd no better in their Country, when you thus flout a reverend Gentleman, becauſe he is new come over, and can't underſtand our Language.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="17" type="jest">
               <head>17.</head>
               <p>A Conſtable whoſe Name was <hi>Nott,</hi> being upon the Watch, a jolly Fellow who had ſome little knowledge of him, was brought before him; and then de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manding where the Conſtable was, the other ſtrutting with his Staff in his hand, ſaid I am he. You are <hi>Nott</hi> the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable, <hi>reply'd the other.</hi> Then ſaid Mr. Conſtable, <hi>Nott,</hi> I ſay, I am the Conſtable; and that you ſhall find, to
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:35696:89"/>your ſorrow, if you dare deny my Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority once more. You do not hear me, <hi>reply'd the other,</hi> deny your Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity; for I ſay, you are <hi>Nott</hi> the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable. Well, ſaid the Regent of the Nocturnal Band of Bill-men, Take him to the Counter. And the next Morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, it being canvaſs'd before a Juſtice, and the Conſtable's Ignorance appearing, in not knowing his own Name, when he heard it, he was order'd to pay the Fees; and give the Party he had com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted a Treat of a Guinea, to be Friends with him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="18" type="jest">
               <head>18.</head>
               <p>A luſty Wench coming out of the Country, and living with the Beadle of the Pariſh, an old Watchman made Love to her: who having ſtay'd a long time, without ever being asked the Queſtion; and ſearing, if ſhe miſs'd this Opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity, never to meet with one ſo favou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable again, clapt up the Bargain, and deſired a Neighbour who was going into the Country, to give that little Kindred ſhe had there, an Account of the good Luck ſhe had met with at <hi>London,</hi> in ſo
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:35696:89"/>ſpeedily altering her Condition. The Man, upon his arrival, was received with ſuch Entertainment as their poor Abilities could afford, and all flock'd about him to hear the News, demanding in what Capacity this Husband of their Kinſwoman's was. Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> He is a very reverend Perſon, a careful One, that looks to the City; and is no leſs dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nify'd, than being One of the Elders that ſits in the Gate. All rejoyced at this, concluding him no leſs than an Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derman, or a Colonel of the Train'd Bands: So leaving them thus deceived, ſeveral of them prepared their beſt Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>page, and came up to congratulate <hi>Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rothy</hi>'s Succeſs, in hopes of Rewards and Favours for former Kindneſs: But when they found ſhe had yoak'd with a Noc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turnal Bill-man, whoſe higheſt Income was but Forty Shillings a Quarter, they ſneak'd home again, without ſo much as a <hi>How d'yee, Couſin?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="19" type="jest">
               <head>19.</head>
               <p>A Country Fellow having been to viſit the Univerſity at <hi>Oxford,</hi> and being asked what ſtrange Things he had ſeen
<pb n="160" facs="tcp:35696:90"/>there? Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> many ſtrange Things; but one above the reſt moſt ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mirable. What's that? <hi>ſaid the other.</hi> Oh! <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I ſaw, in one of the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leges, a Dog in a Wheel, Spinning of Roaſt-meat.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="20" type="jest">
               <head>20.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ben. Johnſon,</hi> one day, paſſing over <hi>Covent-Garden,</hi> a lame Beggar followed him, begging hard for an Alms. How now, Fellow! ſays <hi>Ben.</hi> by what Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority do you beg here? diſturbing People with your Clamours, as they paſs along on their lawful Occaſions? Oh, Si<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>! <hi>reply'd he,</hi> I have loſt the Uſe of my Limbs in the Service, and have a Licenſe for it. Ha! (ſays <hi>Ben.</hi>) Is it ſo? — Well, Friend, Lice, I believe you have; but I'm ſure, little or no ſenſe, to beg Mony of a Poet, as Wit is rated in this Age.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="21" type="jest">
               <head>21.</head>
               <p>Some Spaniards being at Sea in a Storm, one of them vowed to offer a Wax Tapour at the Shrine of St. <hi>Agatha,</hi>
                  <pb n="161" facs="tcp:35696:90"/>(to whom they attribute a Power over Winds and Tempeſts) as big as the Main-Maſt, if ſhe would bring him ſafe to Land. Ay! ſays his companion, but where would you get Mony to buy Wax? or a Mold big enough to make it in? Puh! <hi>reply'd he;</hi> never trouble your Head for that; for though I pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe ſuch a one now, yet when I get a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhore, one of Twelve in the Pound ſhall ſerve her turn.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="22" type="jest">
               <head>22.</head>
               <p>A rambling Foot-man that had been to ſee ſome of his quondam Companions in the City, reeling home late, was brought before an Intelligible Conſtable, who demanded who he belong'd to? He, with ſome ſtuttering, told him, to one Mr. <hi>Baxter.</hi> Oh! <hi>reply'd the Man of Night-Rule,</hi> I underſtand you now! You ſay you are Page of the Back-Stairs: Well, well, go about your Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs; I muſt not ſtop ſuch worthy Men as you, who are Officers at Court: And he diſmiſt him accordingly.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="23" type="jest">
               <pb n="162" facs="tcp:35696:91"/>
               <head>23.</head>
               <p>Two Juſtices, in a former Reign, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving gotten a Fellow between them, upon Examination for a trivial Matter, made a mighty Puther, urging him to go on with his Confeſſion. Why tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, my Maſters, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I find my ſelf between Hawk and Buzzard, and can remember no more at this time, and ſo pray'd to be diſmiſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="24" type="jest">
               <head>24.</head>
               <p>A Woman being told by an arch Wagg, of whom ſhe enquired for News, That there was an Order made, That every painful, laborious Man, that had been Cuckolded Three times, ſhould have a Penſion allow'd by the Society of Cuckold-makers in <hi>London.</hi> Will they ſo, <hi>ſaid ſhe?</hi> why, that will be a great help to us; for my poor Husband may juſtly claim Ten Penſions.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="25" type="jest">
               <pb n="163" facs="tcp:35696:91"/>
               <head>25.</head>
               <p>A needy Fellow walking in the Fields and muſing how to get Mony, eſpying in a Tuft of Graſs a heap of <hi>Album Grae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cum,</hi> (as the Learned call it,) or in plain Engliſh, <hi>White Dogs-turd,</hi> he took it up, and caſt in his Mind, how he might make ſome Advantage of it, to ſupply his craving Neceſſities. And finding any thing, in a manner, that had but a hard Name, went off at <hi>London,</hi> among ſome fort of People, he Chriſten'd it <hi>Torvine;</hi> and putting it up in Papers very decently, feigning an Outlandiſh Tone, went about the Streets, crying, <hi>Who buy my</hi> Torvine, <hi>to make you Ready<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>witted, and ſpeak. Truth preſently.</hi> Among others, a Yorkſhire Man, that was to give Evidence in Law-Matter, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving but a bad Memory, thinking by this means to be made an Orator, pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſed a Paper of a Shilling Price, with large Directions how to take it; and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>eing greedy of Knowledge, fell to nib<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ng of it immediately, and then to puttering and ſpawling, crying out, It was a Tyke's Turd. Why, Lau yee
<pb n="164" facs="tcp:35696:92"/>there! <hi>ſaid the other, laughing;</hi> Did I not tell you, it would make you Ready<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>witted, and ſpeak Truth preſently.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="26" type="jest">
               <head>26.</head>
               <p>A Man that had Robb'b a Houſe, being Taken and Condemned at <hi>Paris,</hi> was carried a Mile out of that City to be Hang'd; but could not, all the way he went, forbear laughing at a merry Conceit that came into his Head. Hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Father-Confeſſor chid him for it, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>horting him to be ſerious, and urged him to give him the Reaſon of that ill<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> tim'd Mirth. He told him, He ſhould know the Occaſion of it, before he dy'd <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> And ſo coming to the fatal Place, when he was mounted on the Ladder, he de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired the People to ſing a <hi>Salvo Reginae</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> that is, a Hymn to the Virgin <hi>Mary</hi> Which when they had ended; Now Father, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> you have often told me o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> the Miracles done by St. <hi>Francis,</hi> St. <hi>Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>natius,</hi> and Others; and the Cauſe wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> I laughed, was, To think I ſhould do a great a one as any of them, before <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> die. What's that? <hi>ſaid the Fryer.</hi> Why even, <hi>reply'd he,</hi> to make a company
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:35696:92"/>of Cuckows ſing in the Middle of Winter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="27" type="jest">
               <head>27.</head>
               <p>A romancing Fellow, telling a Story, That in the <hi>Cham</hi> of <hi>Tartary</hi>'s Court, he ſaw a Man of a mighty Stature eat a Load of Hay, all but the Truſs-bands, for a Wager. That's a ſmall matter, <hi>ſaid another,</hi> reſolving to Out-lye him, thought likely to be very true; for I had an Uncle, that was a Woodman, who would make nothing to eat up a Load of Logs for his Breakfaſt, and a Load of Bavins-bands for his Dinner; but they fill'd him ſo, he ſeldome could eat any Supper.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="28" type="jest">
               <head>28.</head>
               <p>A true Toper, that liv'd at the Sign of the <hi>Three Cups,</hi> having a Letter di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected to him by a Friend, the Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription was, <hi>Three Hundred Cupps;</hi> the next time he met him, he asked him how he came to blunder ſo, by a falſe Direction? Oh! <hi>reply'd he,</hi> I knew well enough what I did; for I could
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:35696:93"/>never find but you loved Cups very well, and therefore reſolved not to ſtint you in your number.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="29" type="jest">
               <head>29.</head>
               <p>A Man being very earneſt to know of his Wife, how many of the Ten Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren he had, were his own: But ſhe put him off, ſometimes with Flamms, and at other times with Proteſtations; till at laſt he, impatient of Delay, vow'd he would go to the Cunning-man to be reſolved, if ſhe made any further refuſal. This made the good Woman ſtart, and intreat him not to do it; for ſuch unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Enterprizes might provoke God to take them from him. Well, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> to prevent it, tell me truly. Indeed, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> I will: This, and this, and ſo going on to the number Nine, are yours. And whoſe is the other? <hi>ſaid he.</hi> Nay, Husband, pray don't ask me that? Well, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> to ſave you a Scruple of Conſcience, and to prove my ſelf an honeſt Man, the Parſon ſhall have this for Tythe; for I am ſatisfied he has a Right to it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="30" type="jest">
               <pb n="167" facs="tcp:35696:93"/>
               <head>30.</head>
               <p>Some quibbling Experiments being puſhed about among jovial Companions, ſays one, What think you of this Four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſquare Houſe, now it is likely to rain, if I ſhould ſo order it, that the Rain ſhould fall but on one ſide of it. Why, ſaid another, it cannot be, unleſs you Conjure, and have Power over the Elements. Yes, <hi>ſaid he;</hi> you ſhall ſee the Experience of it, for a two Bottles Wager. Done! <hi>ſays one;</hi> and Done! <hi>ſays the other.</hi> So ſtaying a little while, it began to rain very plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifully. Now, <hi>ſaid one,</hi> you have loſt. No, <hi>ſaid the other,</hi> I have not: And thus I demonſtrate it, <hi>viz.</hi> What you ſee now, is only the Out-ſide of the Houſe on which the Rain falls, but the In-ſide is dry; and if you make me any more than the Out-ſide and the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide of a thing, then I yield my Wager loſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="31" type="jest">
               <pb n="168" facs="tcp:35696:94"/>
               <head>31.</head>
               <p>A Fellow that had got a ſhrewd Wife, ſeeing a Man turmoil'd with an unruly Horſe, cry'd out, Friend! Friend! if you would tame him, Marry him, and I'll warrant you that will do it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="32" type="jest">
               <head>32.</head>
               <p>An Old Man that was very deaf, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to Market to ſell a Cow, a Sharper who obſerv'd his Infirmity, was very diligent in hearkening who cheapen'd; and following one of the Chapmen into an Ale-houſe, who would not come up to the Price, ſaid, Come, Friend, my Father, yonder, (pointing to him tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>routh the Window,) is willing to take your Mony; pay it to me, and the Cow ſhall be deliver'd: ſown the Mony was laid. The Sharper thereupon ſteps to the Old Man, and ſtrikes him earneſt for his Cow, at his own Price; but that he muſt help his Servant to drive her to his Yard, at the lower-end of the Town. To this he conſented; and then calling out him that had bought her really, away
<pb n="169" facs="tcp:35696:94"/>went the Old Man with him whil'ſt the Sharper rubb'd off with the Mony, and left them to ſcuffle it out at Law; till at length, finding themſelves bub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled and cheated, they ended the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troverſie with a Woodcock-Feaſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="33" type="jest">
               <head>33.</head>
               <p>A Plaiſterer and his Boy being em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd to Whiten a Houſe by the Day, were ſo tedious, that tiring the Patience of the Owner, he one day asked the Boy, in his Maſter's abſence, when he thought they would have done? Who reply'd very bluntly, That his Maſter was gone to look for another Jobb; and if he found one, they ſhould make an end of it that Week: but I believe, <hi>continu'd he,</hi> if he miſſes of any other Work, it will be the End of the next Week before we ſhall have finiſh'd this.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="34" type="jest">
               <head>34.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman requiring a Painter to draw him the Proſpect of a ſine Houſe, with a Porter ſtanding at the Gate with
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:35696:95"/>a Staff in his Hand; he did it all well, to content, but the Porter; which part of his Inſtructions he forgot, and was chid for. Why, Sir, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> are you ſo angry? the Butler has only invited him into the Cellar, to drink a Glaſs of Wine! I'll undertake for him, he ſhall be at the Gate in an hours time: And ſo drew him in his proper place.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="35" type="jest">
               <head>35.</head>
               <p>An old rich Citizen, intending to keep himſelf very warm, reſolved to double the Cloth of a Suit he made; that is, to Line the Coat with the ſame; as likewiſe the Breeches: but in the lat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, next his Skin, a Dimmoty Lining was plac'd. The conſcious Taylor thought therefore, in ſuch a caſe, any Cloth would ſave, and therefore re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to ſave that Remnant: in the room of which, he put in an old pain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Cloth that had been uſed in a Play at <hi>Bartholomew-Fair.</hi> When one day, the Party going to Air himſelf, as he was ſtep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping over a Stile, a Snag happen'd to tear his Breeches; and going to look upon the Rent, he eſpy'd two painted De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vils
<pb n="171" facs="tcp:35696:95" rendition="simple:additions"/>threatning, in horrid Shapes, with Much-Forks in their Hands; which made him haſte to pull them off; and looking further, found other Devils tormenting <hi>Dives</hi> in Flames. Starting at this, he ran with them under his Arm to the Taylor, upbraiding him for cheating him; but moſt of all, that he had made him carry Hell-Fire in his Breeches. Mr. Snipp upon this, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſted, with up-liſted Hands and Eyes, that he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>new nothing of it! and wiſh'd he might go to Hell, to find the Cloth thus chang'd, if he did! (craftily mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that under the Shop-board)</p>
            </div>
            <div n="36" type="jest">
               <head>36.</head>
               <p>A brisk young Sempſtreſs having out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>witted many an airy Fop, and ſparkiſh Gallant, was, at laſt, out-witted her ſelf, in this manner: A Town-Shift, in very good Habit, coming into her Shop, cheapen'd and bargain'd for a conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable parcel of Linnen: and then pau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing — ſaid, Oh! I had like to have forgot one thing; I want a Shirt of the largeſt make; it is not for my ſelf, but for one as big agen. She ſhewed him
<pb n="172" facs="tcp:35696:96"/>thereupon ſeveral; but he complained they were too ſtrait: and then ſhe ſhewed him another; which he ſeemed to like, ſaying, Pray, Madam, do me the favour to let me ſee you ſtrip it on over your Cloaths. The which, to pleaſe and humour ſo good a Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, ſhe did. Then he turning her about, to ſee how it ſate, faſten'd pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vately the hinder Lappets, with two la<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ge Pins, thorough her Cloaths, to the hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>der part of her <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>mock; then ſnatch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Linnen he had bargain'd for, off the Counter, out he ran. She there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon followed him, crying, Stop him! Stop him! and haſtily going to pull the Shirt over her Ears, as aſhamed to pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue him in ſuch a Garment, ſhe with it drew up all her Cloaths, and expoſed her naked Poſteriors to the Publick, and ſo ran on, ſtill pulling to get off the Shirt; whil'ſt ſome good Matrons, who ſuppoſed her to be Mad, ſtopped her, ſenſible that ſhe ought to be cover'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hind: Which gave the Sharper an op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity to rub cleverly off with his Booty.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="37" type="jest">
               <pb n="173" facs="tcp:35696:96"/>
               <head>37.</head>
               <p>A Citizen, not much acquainted with Horſe-Fleſh, ſeeing a very ſine Mare manag'd in her Paces, commended her highly: but, ſaid he, her often breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing will ſpoil her; therefore, it were better they could clap a pair of Stones between her Legs, and make her a Gelding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="38" type="jest">
               <head>38.</head>
               <p>A Citizen having married a very young Girl, and of as young an Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, being invited to a Chriſt'ning, ſhe took the Child in her Arms, and fell to dandling it, the better to be expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rienc'd, when one ſhe long'd for came to town: And how old is this Child? <hi>ſays ſhe to the Nurſe.</hi> Why truly, <hi>reply'd the Nurſe,</hi> but Five Days. Nay, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> I know by my little <hi>Spot,</hi> it muſt be Nine Days old, or it could not ſee. At this the Nurſe laugh'd, and told her, ſhe would be better inform'd, when ſhe came to Years of Diſcretion.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="174" facs="tcp:35696:97"/>
            <head>THE NEW ART OF <hi>Wheedling.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE Word WHEEDLE, is of ſo late an Edition, that it is to be found in no Dictionary but the Canting one; and imports, a ſubtle Inſinuation into the Nature, Humours and Incli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations of ſuch as we converſe with; working upon them ſo effectually, that we poſſeſs them with a Belieſ, that all our Actions and Services tend to their Pleaſure and Profit: Whereas it is but ſeemingly ſo, that we may work on them our Ends, and real Advantage. Therefore, that People may the better ſee thorough this Veil of Hypocriſie, I ſhall lay open the ſlye Methods, the
<pb n="175" facs="tcp:35696:97"/>ſubtle <hi>Wheedler</hi> takes to bring about his Purpoſes.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Practiſed Wheedle,</hi> as <hi>Juvenal</hi> ſays of ſuch Men in his time, will conform to all ſorts of Company: Do you laugh; they will endeavour to laugh louder: If you are ſad and penſive, and prove to weep, they will deluge themſelves in Crocadilian Tears: If you complain of Cold; they Shiver: and if, in the next breath, you ſay the Weather's Warm; they'll ſtrait begin to Unbutton, and cry, they are ſwelter'd with Heat.</p>
            <q>
               <l>—Ridens? Majore cachinno</l>
               <l>Concucitur: flet, ſi Lachrynas conſpexit Amici,</l>
               <l>Nec dolet, igniculum Brumae ſi tempore poſcas,</l>
               <l>Accipit Endromidem, ſi dixeris, aeſtuo, ſudat.</l>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Juven. Sat. 4.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>The <hi>Wheedle</hi> will be ſure never whol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to diſapprove what any one ſays, on whom he has a Deſign: But if he ſays any thing never ſo improbable, or im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible, if he makes not an Apology for it, he will not wholly contradict it, but even his Negative; like <hi>Janus,</hi> ſhall bear a double Face; and without feeling any of your Paſſions, or underſtanding
<pb n="176" facs="tcp:35696:98"/>any of your Actions, he ſhall appear more concerned for you than you are for your ſelves, and fail not to compoſe and conform his Countenance and Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtures exactly with yours; and <hi>Proteus</hi> like, turn himſelf into any ſhape of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſation that may prove profitable or advantageous to him. It is not every one can make a compleat <hi>Wheedle;</hi> for it requires many Qualifications; as, ſome Learning, good Natural Parts, and a Comely Body; alſo, a practis'd Reſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, Diſſimulation, Flattery, bridl'd or pretended Patience, Humility, Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity, Plauſibility, Affability; a ſeeming Honeſty, though none in the bottom: So that Men are cheated by them, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore their Eyes; and perſuaded, by cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Inſinuations, out of their Reaſons, to believe theſe Flatterers before their own Senſes; who, with the Poet, thus whiſper to them:
<q>
                  <l>—Da Juſtum, Sanctum<expan>
                        <am>
                           <g ref="char:abque"/>
                        </am>
                        <ex>que</ex>
                     </expan> videri:</l>
                  <l>Noctem peccatis, &amp; Fraudibus: jobjece Nubem.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>"Let me ſeem Juſt and Holy: Let the "Night</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>"O'er-caſt my Frauds: Let Clouds "hide them from ſight.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <pb n="177" facs="tcp:35696:98"/>
            <p>And now for his Qualifications. And the Firſt of theſe are (as is ſaid) Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or Languages acquired by Travel: For though he may often meet with Bubbles and Blockheads, he may ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times, for all his Cunning, catch a Tar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tar, meet with ſuch as will find him out to be only a ſilly Pretender to what he profeſſes, and by which he has gained ſo much Applauſe; and if he loſes his Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit, his Company falls off, and he is left to ſhift, till in a place that he is not known, he can faſten upon others.</p>
            <p>The next, is, good Natural Parts; a fluent way of Diſcourſing, without Heſitation or Stammering, having all his Words prompt and ready, apt to turn and wind; and when an Ambiguity is deliver'd, to turn it to the beſt advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage; and ſo if he finds, at firſt, he trips of miſtakes, he may, upon ſecond thoughts, rectifie his Underſtanding.</p>
            <p>Thirdly, A Handſome, Proportion'd Body, and a winning Preſence and Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haviour, which wins and attracts Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection, if ſuited with a genteel Garb, eſpecially on the Female Sex, on whom they chiefly employ their Talent; ſo
<pb n="178" facs="tcp:35696:99"/>that by ingratiating into their Favour, they have many of them ſhared Eſtates with the Husband, and liv'd ſplen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>didly, without any other Stock than their Tongues, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Theſe Qualifications being had, the next thing they do, is to haunt the Coffee-Houſes, Taverns, Gaming-Ordinaries, and ſuch like Places, to obſerve, by the Behaviour and Demeanour of the Party, what Stock of Underſtanding he has, but more eſpecially, what Stock of Mony or Supplies belonging to him; and the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> he ſixes the firſt Opportunity he can take hold of, on a Bottle of Wine, or a ſmall Collation; which Generoſity he undeniably accepts of; and then, by humouring in all his pretty Fancies, make him believe he is the moſt accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhed Gentleman he ever met with in the days of his born; and from that moment, they contract an intimate fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miliarity, and are ſeldom aſunder, till ſuch time as the Gallant's Exchequer, by reaſon of the profuſe Extravagancy, begins to be at low Ebb; and then, like a Swallow, he goes off with a canting Complement, to a warmer Sun. When
<pb n="179" facs="tcp:35696:99"/>he ſees an Opportunity, he borrows, with Promiſes and Proteſtations of Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, when his Eſtate, which he pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ends is very large, after the Death of his Father, comes into Hands: And if his new <hi>Amicus</hi> is not free in that, then he gets himſelf Arreſted by ſome of his Companions; and ſo ſending for his Friend, tells him a lamentable Story, That he had the misfortune to be obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged for a young Gentlewoman, to a Taylor, for Twenty Pounds; and that ſhe being gone down to her Relations, to fetch up the Mony, her Creditor be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing poſſeſs'd by one whom ſhe rivals in Beauty and Amours, That ſhe has with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drawn her ſelf, on purpoſe to cheat him, he has Arreſted him at a nick of time when he is out of Mony, but ſhall receive an Hundred Pounds in four days.</p>
            <p>The kind good natur'd Gentleman, upon this, opens his Purſe; or if he be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nſurniſhed, borrows of his wealthy Friends, to ſupply his wheedling One; and by this means the ſupports his Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure and Riot: Theſe kind of Cattle being like <hi>Pharaoh</hi>'s lean Kine, the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vourers of all the Young Sparks that fall in their courſe to be ſo unfortunate as to be acquainted with them.</p>
            <pb n="180" facs="tcp:35696:100"/>
            <p>So briefly to conclude, I ſhall end in theſe Lines of a witty Author:
<q>
                  <l>When the young Fop comes fluttering up to Town</l>
                  <l>From an indulgent Mother, up and down</l>
                  <l>He rambles, till at laſt he is eſpy'd</l>
                  <l>By ſome ſharp Knave, and is by him decoy'd</l>
                  <l>Into a Snare, by's ſmooth, deluding Tongue,</l>
                  <l>Who, <hi>Syren</hi> like, does lead him, lull'd along</l>
                  <l>In a fond waking Dream, till he, at laſt,</l>
                  <l>Too late for Reſcue, is on Quick-ſands caſt;</l>
                  <l>There ſadly ſees how he has been deceiv'd;</l>
                  <l>And comfortleſs, is of his Friends bereav'd;</l>
                  <l>Left in a Goal, at leiſure to repent,</l>
                  <l>And there converſe with Want and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>content:</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Wheedle</hi> then him, as Contagion, flies,</l>
                  <l>And there, without ſome true Friend's help, he lies</l>
                  <l>In Miſery, perhaps, until he dies.</l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:35696:100"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
